东西都带全了吗
So you got everything?
你打算在飞机上一直玩游戏
You gonna play video games all flight
还是打算真的看会书
or do you think you might actually crack open a book?
大概会看会书
Probably read some.
别害怕给我回邮件 好吗
If I write you an e-mail, don't be scared to write me back.
让老爸了解下你的想法和近况
Ok? It won't kill you to let your old man know
又不会要了你的命
what you're thinking about or what is going on, you know?
好的
Yeah.
你愿意的话
If you want,
咱们每周可以用网络电话聊聊天
we can try Skyping once a week or something.
好的
All right.
自然科学课画的那些图纸带了吗
You got the drawings for your science deal?
- 应该带了  - 好吧
- Yeah. I think so.  - Alright.
你做得很好 真的特别棒
Well, they turned out great by the way, like really great.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 你的电脑充好电了吗  - 充好了
- Is your computer charged?  - Yeah.
等你到家以后
What do you think is the first thing
你第一件要做的事是什么
you are going to do when you get home?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我很珍惜咱们这次交流的机会
I really cherish this communication we have, you know.
- 只是你的回答都有点…  - 怎么了
- It's just... your answers are so...  - What?
坚持练习弹钢琴 好吗
Just keep practicing the piano, Ok?
你弹得很棒
You're really good
而且你都费了那么大功夫了
and they spend so much time at that school of yours.
别忘了音乐这东西
Just... just remember that music is actually something
会有助于你的生活
that you'll use in your life.
别忘了…你要芝麻味的 对吧
Don't forget to... you want those sesame things right?
那种特好吃
They're really good.
好的
Yeah.
你好
Γεια σου!
谢谢
Thank you.
我大概十月能过去
I probably make it over there in October.
我会尽量赶去看你的第一次独奏
I'll try to see you in that first recital
最好还能赶上看你踢场球赛
and hopefully catch a soccer game while I'm there.
谢谢
Ευχαριστώ!
今年我可能不会再踢足球了
I might not even play soccer this year.
这绝对是个错误的决定 相信我
That would be a big mistake, trust me.
我踢得不好
I'm not that good.
不 你踢得很好 非常好
Oh no, you're pretty good, you are.
可是…我错过了夏季训练营
I mean... I missed summer training camp,
所以不太可能让我回去了
so the chances of me starting are miniscule.
你直接告诉教练你的情况
Yes, well, just tell the coach your situation.
你爸爸住在欧洲 你其实特想去
Your dad lives in Europe and you really wanted to be there.
就是之类的借口 把责任推给我
You know... blah, blah, blame me,
我父母太讨厌了 但是我很上心的
my parents stink but I'm really serious.
但是我没那么上心 爸爸
But I'm not serious, Dad.
我不是很在意那个
I don't care that much.
你也不用现在就做决定 多考虑考虑
Well, you don't have to decide right now, just think about it.
我就是觉得团队运动很重要
All I'm saying is that team sports are important.
就到这儿了
Here we are.
我喜欢这个机场 你呢
I love this airport, don't you?
这里太酷了
It's awesome.
是吧 我也觉得很酷
Yeah, I know it's cool, right?
要见到你妈妈了 兴奋吗
Are you excited about seeing your mom?
- 是啊 还有我的伙伴们  - 没错
- Yeah, and all my friends.  - Yeah.
你的登机牌和护照都带了吗
What about your boarding pass, passport?
好的 转机你没问题吧
Ok... Do you feel confident about making the connection?
没事 我以前都是这样的
Yes, I have done this before.
但这次有点复杂
Yes, but this is a tricky connection.
飞机着陆后 记着坐着别起来
Just remember that when you land you stay in your seat,
会有航空公司的人来接你
somebody from the airline is going to come get you
把你带去登机口
and take you to the gate.
记住了吗
Ok?
- 没问题的  - 好吧
- It's not a problem.  - Ok, alright.
伙计
Oh boy.
看来真的得说再见了 是吧
Well... it looks like maybe we should just do this thing, huh?
过来 天啊
Ok, come here! Oh, God.
我会尽量赶去看你独奏的 好吗
I'll do my best to make that recital, Ok?
其实…我不介意的
You know... I wouldn't bother.
为什么这么说
What makes you say that?
我不是故意要刻薄你
Look, I'm not being mean,
但如果你不来看我独奏的话我会更轻松
but it would be easier if you didn't come to the recital.
怎么会呢
How come?
如果你选别的周末来看我更好
It would just be better if you visited on a nothing weekend.
我想看你弹琴
I want to see you play.
但是妈妈真的很讨厌你
Look. It's because mom hates you so much.
如果你在 她会特别紧张
She would be really stressed if you were there
弄得我也很有压力
and then it would be tense for me.
- 你知道吗  - 谢谢
- You know...  - Thank you.
而且咱们也没有时间一起玩
We wouldn't have any time to hang out anyway.
别担心 会有办法的
Do not worry about it, we'll figure that out.
我不希望你担心这个 好吗
I just don't want you to worry about it, you know?
你知道我有多想你 对吧
I mean... You know how much I miss you, right?
你为什么觉得她还那么讨厌我
Why do you think she still hates me so much?
我不知道
I don't know!
我觉得相比起来她更讨厌丹尼尔一些
I think she hates Daniel more than she hates you.
好吧
Yeah.
别担心 我会想办法的
Hey, don't worry about it, I'll figure something out.
我该进去了
We should just do this.
好的 还有什么我能帮忙的吗
Yeah, but is there anything I can do to help?
我不知道
I don't know.
- 但是你知道我爱你 对吗  - 当然
- But you know that I love you, right?  - Yeah.
我当然知道 这是我过得最好的一个夏天
Yeah, I know! This has been the best summer of my life!
- 真的吗  - 真的
- Really?  - Yeah!
我也这么想 看吧
For me too, see?
我就说过希腊会是个特别棒的地方
I told you, this whole Greece thing was going to be great.
确实是
And it was.
我爱你 伙计
Ok! I love you, pal.
我也爱你 爸爸
I love you too, Dad.
来 握个手
Ok... shake my hand.
再见
Bye!
好的 好的
Oui, oui!
他跟德国人有个合作项目
Il a un projet avec les Allemands.
像往常一样
Comme d'habitude.
卡拉玛塔机场
听我说 会议气氛太压抑了
écoutez, on est stressé en cette réunion...
不 不 我是说下周
Non, bah, non. La semaine prochaine j'ai dit oui.
爱在午夜降临前
好的 那太好了
Ok, bon, très bien.
谢谢 您也一样 再见
Merci, oui, oui, vous aussi hein. Au revoir.
我被排除在外了
Ah, j'suis débusquée.
- 怎么了  - 他们投票反对
- What's going on?  - They voted against it!
反对什么 安装风力涡轮机吗
What? The wind turbines?
和这些人打了六个月的交道
6 months dealing with these people,
好不容易都同意了
they were all for it.
大家都认为这对地区有好处
Everyone agreed it was great for the region.
那出什么岔子了
So what happened?
现在他们都觉得涡轮机
Now they've decided that they don't like the way
放在山上的样子不好看
that it looks on that hill.
他们说那样有碍观瞻
It's "Ruining their view."
这件事不是都定下来了吗
I thought it was a done deal.
是啊 当时都说定了
It was! It practically was.
那他们怎么还能这么做
Can they do that?
当然 他们就这么做了 这事儿完了
Of course! They've done it, and it's over.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
没事 我只是太沮丧了
No, no, it's so frustrating.
我忍不下去了
I can't take it anymore.
我要接海米尔那活了
I'm gonna take that job with Hemir.
别 你不想为他们工作
No, you do not wanna work for them.
- 为什么  - 为政府工作吗
- Why not?  - For the government?
我觉得这届政府和以往不同
I think this government is different.
我们需要法律支持 这是唯一的办法
We need laws and it's the only way anything is gonna happen.
总有别的法子的
That's not the only way,
你们已经做了很多不错的工作了
you guys have been getting a lot of good work done.
我考虑过了 只有这办法行得通
Well, I've been thinking about it, this is the way to go.
好吧 那你可别忘了
Ok, well then let me remind you
你和那人合不来
that you do not like that guy.
以前你在他那工作的时候
The whole time you worked for him before
你整天都在抱怨
you complained about him constantly.
没错 他是个混蛋
Yeah, yeah, yeah... He can be an asshole
但是他能帮我把事搞定
but he gets things done.
从现在开始我就得这么想了
That's how I'm gonna be from now on.
- 好吧  - 我要做个贱人
- Ok.  - A real bitch, Ok?
每次我见他都觉得他是狼子野心
Well, every time I look at that guy all I see is ambition.
对不起 我就是不信任他
I mean, I'm sorry, I don't trust him.
他从非营利部门转入政府的唯一原因
The only reason he's going from not for profit to government
就是想有人能拍他马屁
is to have people kiss his ass.
我不在乎他怎么样 好吗
I don't care about him, Ok?
好吧 我就是觉得你会过得特痛苦
Ok, I think you are gonna be miserable.
面对数不清的政治活动和协商会议
With all the politicking and compromise.
无所谓
Whatever.
我已经决定了
I've made my decision.
典出古希腊神话中诸神对西西弗斯的惩罚，让他每每接近成功又前功尽弃
我不想再做把大石头推上山
I'm tired of being the do-gooder who rolls a boulder up a hill
再看着它滚下来的老好人了
and watches it roll down again.
他以前不是经常
Wasn't he the guy who used to throw his pens
扔笔砸他的助理吗
at his assistants and stuff?
我一年前就该接这份工作了
Ok, I should have taken this job a year ago.
我害怕是因为工作量太大
And I was scared because of the amount of work
但是我觉得这是个绝好的机会
but I think it's the best opportunity ever.
工资也更高 我决定了
And it's more money, and I'm doing it.
好吧 你确定吗
Ok, are you sure?
不确定 我什么都不确定 行吗
No, I'm not sure of anything, Ok?
如果我走了 那其他人都怎么办
I mean, what's gonna happen to everyone if I leave?
弗朗索瓦他们都指着我呢
Like Francois... I mean, they count on me.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
我该不该接那个工作
Should I take it or not?
不 不 我不发表意见
Oh, no no no, I don't have an opinion.
我只是不想你因为风力涡轮机的失败
No, I just don't want to see you rush into a decision
就匆忙做出决定
because this wind turbine crap is gone.
不仅是因为那个 好吗
It's not just that, Ok?
我都蠢蠢欲动一整个夏天了
It's been stirring me all summer.
- 不 我知道的  - 我要接这个工作 我决定了
- No, I know it has, I know.  - I should do it. I'm doing it!
那就接吧
Then do it.
我决定了 好吗
I'm doing it! Alright?
上帝啊 我真希望事情都能简单些
Oh God, I wish that things were simpler.
我走也完蛋 我留也完蛋
I mean... if I leave I get fucked, if I stay I get fucked.
永远都不确定
It's always a guess.
没错 这就是个操蛋的世界
Yeah, the world is fucked.
我觉得也是
Yeah, maybe.
天啊 好不容易能度个假期了
Oh God, we finally have a vacation,
头两个星期姑娘们还生病了
and the girls are sick for the first two weeks.
我明白
I know.
有个完美儿子 却还住在一百万英里外
With the perfect son who lives a million miles away.
或者是你毕生所爱
Or the love of your life
刮完胡子不知道清理下
who can't clean up after himself
还不肯学学怎么刮胡子
or learn how to shave.
谁说的
Who said that?
你不是在说这的清洁队队长吧
You're not talking about Captain Clean-up over here?
清洁队队长
Captain Clean-up?
那个在行动中都失踪了好几年的人
The one that's been missing in action all these years.
这时候你希望我说什么
What did you expect at this point?
上帝啊
God.
瞧瞧她们 太可爱了
Oh look at them, they're so cute.
就像连体婴儿似的
They look like conjoined twins.
天啊 我得给她们照张相
Oh my God, I'm gonna take a picture of this.
艾拉那个苹果吃完了吗
Hey, did Ella finish that apple?
你要从孩子嘴里抢食吃吗
You're going to take food out of your child's mouth?
- 是的  - 好吧
- Yeah.  - Ok.
都变成棕色了
This all brown.
没关系 还有一块可以吃
No no, there is a spot here.
艾拉 这是你爸爸偷你食物的证据
Ella, this is evidence of your father stealing food from you.
不管你变得贪食还是厌食
If you become bulimic or anorexic,
都不是我的错 别全怪你妈妈 好吗
it's not my fault, don't blame it all on your mother, Ok?
艾拉 这是个家庭分享苹果
Ella, this is a family apple.
我在教她们分享的重要性
I'm teaching them the value of sharing.
宝贝我爱你
I love you, honey.
多甜蜜啊 姑娘们会比咱们还要深刻地
Ahhh, so sweet, you girls will remember this vacation
铭记着这次与众不同的假期
very different than we will.
那是肯定的
That's for sure.
从我妈那里我就知道了
I see that with my mom,
她对我童年的印象和我完全不同
she remembers my childhood entirely different than I do.
别拍我了
Please stop filming me.
天啊 我爱你妈妈 你对她太苛刻了
God. I love your mom, you're always so hard on her.
因为你错过了那些操蛋的岁月
It is because you missed the fucked-up years,
你赶上了好时候
you are just getting the good era.
操蛋的岁月
The fucked-up years.
说到操蛋我想起来了
That reminds me, talking about fucked-up,
我告诉过你我那只艳后猫咪的事吗
did I ever tell you the story about my little Cleopatra kitty?
我记不得了 我要是说过你肯定有印象
I dunno? Ok. I think you would remember if I did.
故事是这样的
It's the story.
我小时候养了只猫 起名叫埃及艳后
You know when I was a little girl I had this cat named Cleopatra.
每到春天她都会跳出栅栏然后怀孕
And every spring she would jump the fence and get pregnant.
每次都会生出恰好两只猫咪
And always end up with a litter of exactly two kittens.
- 恰好两只  - 每次 每年都是两只
- Two kitties.  - Every time, every year, two cats.
很神奇 在我三十岁左右的某一天
I mean... it's just amazing, then one days I was like around 30.
我和我爸爸一起吃午饭 回忆过去
And I was having lunch with my dad and was remembering,
提到了小埃及艳后
mentioning little Cleopatra.
他说自己做过最艰难的事
And he was like... the hardest thing I ever had to do
就是杀掉那些可爱的小猫咪
was to kill those cute little kittens.
我惊讶极了
And I was like what?!
我告诉你 其实就是这么回事
It turns out ... listen to this.
有时她会一窝生出七只猫咪
There was sometimes up to 7 kittens in that litter.
我爸爸就拿走五只
But he would take 5 of them,
把它们放进一个塑料袋 然后灌乙醚
put them in a plastic bag, with a bunch of ether.
太可怕了
That is terrible.
就好像 他似乎忘记了
That was like... He had forgotten
当初他和妈妈是怎么骗我的了
the lie he and my mum had told me about the kittens.
他怎么决定该杀哪几只呢
How did he decide which ones he wanted to kill?
其实我倒真问过他
Well actually I asked him that.
是不是拿走最毛茸茸的 最可爱的
Did you take the, you know, the fluffiest, cutest?
然后他就开始哭 可怜的老爸
You know, and he just started to cry, poor daddy.
咱们说过要在这里停车的
Oh we said we would gonna stop.
孩子们要看遗迹
They wanted to see the ruins.
- 没错  - 艾拉特想看
- Yeah.  - Well, Ella really wanted to ...
是的 但是咱们该把她们叫醒吗
Yes, but should we wake them up?
咱们回机场的路上可以叫她们看
You know, on the way back to the airport, we can catch them.
- 咱们不会的  - 没错 大概是
- You know we won't.  - Yeah, probably not.
再见了古代遗迹 不过你有什么好看的
So long ancient ruins! What is so great about you, anyway?
窥一斑可见全豹
You seen one, you seen them all.
天啊 咱们真是对糟糕的父母
Oh my God, we are shitty parents.
咱们应该停车的
We should have stopped.
- 没事的  - 这是文化 掉头吧
- It's Ok.  - It's culture, come on, go back.
咱们得培养她们一些品质
We gotta put some character to these kids somehow.
咱们在教她们重要的一课
I mean, we are teaching them a valuable lesson.
在这世上 如果你睡过了 就错过了
If you snooze, you lose in this world.
然后等姑娘们进了戒毒所
And when the girls are in rehab suffering from
遭受十年的吸毒成瘾时
10 years of addiction to cocaine and speed.
她们会说 我只是从来都睡不踏实
They'll say, you just never felt comfortable going to sleep.
因为我们爸爸总是告诉我们说
Because our daddy always used to tell us
睡过了就错过了
that if you snooze, you lose.
这就又是你的错了
And that will be your fault, again.
- 咱们真是糟糕的父母  - 我知道
- Well we are shitty parents.  - I know.
和汉克告别糟透了
Saying goodbye to Hank sucked.
为什么 他不高兴吗
Why? Was he upset?
没有 他说这是他过得最好的暑假
No. He said it was the best summer of his life.
那很好啊 我不会太担心他的
Well that's great. I mean, I would not worry too much about him.
我们聊了很多
We spoke a bunch.
你知道他这辈子最关心什么吗
You know what his main concerns in life are?
什么
What?
青春痘和女孩子们对他的感觉
Pimples and how girls perceive him.
真是有其父必有其子
The apple doesn't fall far far from the tree I guess.
我才不是那样呢
I'm not like that.
拜托 你脑子里只有这个
Oh please! That's all you think about!
- 什么啊  - 女人啊
- What!  - Women!
我不是在抱怨
I mean... I'm not complaining.
我占用了你大部分精力
I'm getting a lot of attention.
- 但你总是在向姑娘抛媚眼  - 我没有
- But you never stop ogling girls.  - I don't ogle girls.
我不送秋波 我用眼神传达爱意
I don't ogle girls. I make love to them with my eyes.
我喜欢这个西班牙人 她是不是希腊人
Oh wow... I like the Spanish guy or is it Greek?
我不知道我来自何方 但我体毛旺盛
I do not know where I am from, but I'm very hairy.
我觉得 亨利可能有点
Well I think... you know... Henry might of...
- 怎么了  - 那个叫梅丽娜的小姑娘
- What?  - That little, Melina girl.
我不知道 他心动了 但是
I don't know. He had a crush, but...
你开玩笑吧
Are you kidding?
你觉得他为什么说这是最好的一个暑假
Why do you think he said it was the best summer of his life?
因为我们一起度过了快乐的时光吗
Because he and I had a good time together?
上帝啊
Jesus.
- 所以呢 你觉得他们接吻了吗  - 当然了
- So what? Do you think they kissed?  - Of course.
没错 接吻了 是的
Yeah, they kissed, yeah, yeah.
我发誓要保密的
I was sworn to secrecy
但是他告诉我他们接吻了
but he told me they kissed.
他怎么说的
What did he say?
我不应该告诉你的
I'm not supposed to tell you anything,
我不说了
so I'm not gonna talk.
- 说吧  - 好吧
- Come on!  - Ok!
他告诉我他在琢磨接吻的事
He told me he was concerned about the kissing.
而且是舌吻
You know tongue to tongue.
是的
Yeah.
但是他太可爱了
But he was... he was so cute,
紧张的脸通红 还咬着腮帮子
all nervous, all red, biting his cheek.
所以他和梅丽娜是认真的
So he and Melina were a real thing.
- 没错  - 那现在会发生什么
- Yeah.  - What's gonna happen now?
不知道
I don't know.
先做朋友 在脸书上互动
They must be friends, facebook...
他们至少会保持一段时间联系
They'll keep in touch at least for a while.
如果他们从此就共度余生了呢
Hey, what if they end up spending all their life together?
你太俗气了
You're so corny.
有时候我真觉得
Sometime's I'm just like...
真的吗 你以为你还是个十二岁的小姑娘
Are you? What are you? A 12-year-old girl?
你还记得你的初恋是谁吗
With your first love, do you even remember who it was?
我记得 是你
Yeah I do. It was you.
拜托 说得好像你二十三岁还是处男似的
Oh, please, like you were a virgin at 23.
我说的是初恋 不是第一次性经历
I said first love not first sexual experience.
好吧
Ok. Fine.
就是说我是你第一个爱上的女人
Like I'm the first woman you have ever fell in love with?
- 差不多  - 我觉得不是
- Yeah pretty much.  - i don't think so.
第一个我觉得心灵相通的女人
the first one I felt truly connected to.
怎么 我不是你的初恋吗
What? I wasn't your first love?
不 当然不是
No, of course not.
我还以为我是呢
No, I just thought I was.
- 杰西 别这样 太蠢了  - 不 没事 没关系的
- Jesse, stop this. It's dumb.  - No, it's Ok, it's not a big deal.
好吧 你多大了都
No. Ok, how old are you? Come on!
年底就整四十一岁了
41 on the last of the year.
咱们那晚你真的是费了老大劲了
You are so, so working on our little night.
勇士照我去战斗
I got a trojan in my billfold
哥们有根大火箭
and a rocket in my pocket.
我和一个美国青少年耗在一起了
I'm stuck with an American teenager.
我真不敢相信
I can't believe it,
咱们一会真要做那些事吗
do we have to do all that stuff later?
什么事 对了
What? Oh yeah, c'mon,
那对帕特里克来说很重要的
it means a lot to Patrick.
阿里阿德涅和斯特凡诺斯估计已经准备
Ariadni and Stefanos are probably already there
和孩子们再来一次快乐时光了
prepping the kids want to have one more big time.
- 不 不是  - 会很有趣的
- No, no.  - It's going to be fun.
不是 我是说之后去旅馆的事
No, I meant the hotel later.
我不是特别想去 你好 亲爱的
I'm not sure I want to go there... Hi, sweetie.
是的
Yeah.
好吧 好的 好的
Oh, Ok, Ok, Ok.
没事的
It's fine.
到伦敦给我打电话 旅途愉快 再见
Call me from London, have a good flight, bye.
飞机上说把电子设备都关掉
They were telling them to turn everything off.
他们要起飞了
They were about to take off
我叫他上了飞机给我打电话
and I asked him to call me from the plane.
我不喜欢他坐飞机
You know I don't like when he flies.
怎么了
What?
- 怎么了  - 我也不知道
- What is it?  - I just. I don't know.
我不确定我能一直这样下去
I just don't think I can keep doing this.
哪样
What?
每个暑假 每个圣诞节 就像是
Just every summer, every Christmas, you know, it's like..
我明白 我也不舒服
I know. It makes me uncomfortable.
不应该这么糟糕的
It just wouldn't be so bad.
要是我们把他送到寄宿学校
If I... If we were sending him to boarding school or something.
我不知道
I don't know.
要是我跟他妈妈的关系能缓和点
If his mom and I got along a little bit better.
我知道 像亲手把他送回敌人的阵线去
I know, it's like we're sending him back across enemy lines.
这次我真的没法无所谓
It really hit me this time, you know?
他就要去读高中了 整整四年啊
He's gonna be a freshman in high school 4 more years,
要开始学会独立了
and he's gonna be on his own.
也许是件好事
Maybe that's the good news,
我们也只有四年…
we only have four more years of this...
不 现在是关键时刻
No, no, this is the crucial time,
我就觉得自己应该陪着他
I just feel I should be there for him, you know.
不然就没机会了 你懂吗
Like it's now or never, you know?
我不懂 你什么意思
No. what do you mean?
我知道总有一天
I thought that somehow he would
他会离开我们
end up living with us, somewhere along the way.
时光飞逝 当你有所察觉时
Time has gone by so fast and look,
他已经要上高中了
here we are it's high school.
然后是谈恋爱 再来就该申请大学了
It's girls, and next thing you know, is College applications.
是的 没错 也许是时候了
Yeah, you're right, maybe it's time,
我真的觉得是时候告诉他妈妈这一切
I mean, I really think it's time to tell his mom all this,
问她愿不愿意让孩子跟我们一块住
and ask if he can live with us.
孩子肯定很乐意
He'd love it!
这是绝对不可能的 好吗
That's never gonna happen. Right?
除了法定义务 她什么都不会给我的
She will never give me one thing she is not legally obligated to.
还要不要找回那个律师
Do you want to call that lawyer again?
不要 我不喜欢他 他很差劲
No, I don't like that guy, he's terrible.
要我打给孩子他妈吗
Should I call his mother?
不要 别再打了
No, please. Never again.
他甚至还不懂怎么扔棒球
I mean the kid doesn't even know how to throw a baseball!
谁在乎啊
Who cares.
他用肘发力 扔得跟小女生一样
He just, he eads with his elbow, he throws like a girl.
这不能怪你
It's not your fault.
不 就都怪我
No, it is my fault,
父亲就该教会儿子这些
a father is supposed to teach you that.
他只是不喜欢打棒球 不能怪他
Ok. he just doesn't like baseball, you can't blame him.
我只是用这个例子来比喻做其他事情
It's just an example, it's a metaphor for everything.
他马上就十四岁了 他需要父亲的陪伴
He's turning 14 and he needs to be with his father.
杰西 我是不会搬去芝加哥的
Jesse, I'm not moving to Chicago.
什么 我有说吗
What? Did I ask you to?
你怎么会这样想
Where did that come from?
我只是想到什么说什么
I'm just thinking out loud.
我曾经答应过自己不要这么冲动
I mean, this is the one thing I promised myself I would never do.
现在我看开了 冲动就冲动吧
And I look up and I'm doing it!
听着 你是个好父亲
Listen, you're a wonderful father.
他珍惜这段父子关系
He loves the relationship you have,
他珍惜你给他写的信
he loves the letters you send him.
我的信他连看都没看
He doesn't even read the letters.
他当然看了你的信
Of course he reads them,
他只是没有给你回…
he just doesn't complement the writing the way you want...
我只是知道 要是错过了这几年
I just know that if I miss these years,
就永远也补不回来了
they are never coming back.
老天
Oh my God.
怎么了
What?
这就是结束的时刻
This is where it ends.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
- 这就是人们分手的节奏  - 老天
- This is how people start breaking up.  - Oh my god.
- 不是的  - 你这是小题大做
- No, no, no.  - You just jumped off a cliff.
不是 我要记下今天
No, no. I'm marking this,
就在今天 你引爆了
this is the day you light the ticking bomb,
了结我们性命的定时炸弹
that will destroy our lives, yeah?
好的 首先
Ok, well, first off,
不是引爆定时炸弹
you don't light a ticking bomb,
而是安装 它有定时器
you set it, it has a timer.
- 所以才能定时  - 是吗 管他呢
- That's why it ticks.  - Oh, yeah. whatever.
现在已经开始倒计时了
You know what? It's ticking right now.
说什么也没用
And this is how it happens.
你自己不高兴
You are unhappy and blame it
却怪别人满怀怨恨
on the other person Resentment grows,
等一切都崩溃了 你就提出分手
everything falls apart and you break up.
- 你就是这样  - 你这样做只是想让我闭嘴
- That's it.  - You are just doing this to shut me up.
不是 根本不是
Not at all! Not at all!
你是 而且你也这样做了
No, you are, and that's what you are doing, yeah.
不是 我是觉得很惊讶
No, I'm actually surprised,
在经历了那么多…
we've lasted this long...
好的 直接说你想说的
Ok. So here it comes out...
我们本形同陌路 但却萍水相逢
We are on parallel tracks a while but now the tracks have crossed,
现在却要分道扬镳了
and I'm going west and you're going east.
就是这样分手的
And believe me this is how it happens.
我早就知道了 就像卡特琳跟亚历山大…
I've seen it, ok? Katrin, Alexandre...
- 你在开玩笑吧  - 没有
- You're kidding, right?  - Well, no.
你可以当玩笑 但我是认真的
I'm kidding, and I'm not.
好吧
Right.
别那么…
Just...
- 就这样了  - 我想看古代遗迹
- This is it.  - I want watch ancient ruins.
那里关门了
Oh, they were closed.
宝贝 下次去机场的时候
Sweetie you know what, we decided to catch them,
我们再去看 好吗
when we're on the way back to the airport. Ok?
没错 我们会早点启程 对吧
Exactly, we'll leave early, right?
是的
Yes!
我的苹果呢
What happened to my apple?
你的苹果…
Your apple...
你的苹果吗 已经被你吃完了啊
Ta pomme, mais elle était finie cette pomme.
是吧
Right?
你们去买冰淇淋吧 我们大概一点出发
Allez vous chercher des glaces, on y passe à une heure.
- 把清单拿来  - 我没拿
- Give me the list.  - I don't have it.
在你钱包里 钱包拿来
It's in your wallet! And your wallet.
我是将军
Ok, I am the General.
妮娜上尉 去帮我找厕纸
Capitaine Nina, vous allez me chercher du papier toillette.
遵命
Oui!
谁任命你当将军的
Who made you General?
我是将军 好吗
The General, ok?
艾拉上尉 您去找卷纸
Capitaine Ella, vous allez chercher les roules papiers
就在商店最里面的右边
qui sont tout au fond du magasin à droite.
- 遵命  - 待命
- Oui!  - à vos ordres!
特别警告 你什么都不许拿
Private Clean-up, you don't touch anything!
好的 长官
D'accord.
别走太快
Il vous faut pas aller trop vite.
妮娜 放到厨房去
Nina, la cuisine.
妮娜 听到没
Nina!
我的队友呢 我的队友呢
Where is my team! Where is my team!
去帮我找点番茄过来
Allez me chercher des tomates.
那边 那边
Là-bas, là-bas!
- 是这个吗  - 是的
- Celles-là?  - Ah... oui!
挑红的
The red one.
- 这个行吗  - 很好
- Celle-là?  - Très bien!
辣椒 接住
Ok! Pepper!
其实两本我都读过
Actually I read them both.
第一本叫《彼时此刻》
The first one is called "That time",
第二本叫《此时此刻》
and the second one is "This time".
不对 第一本叫《此时此刻》
No, the first is "This time",
第二本叫《彼时此刻》
and the second is "That time".
没错
Yeah.
我们还开玩笑 第一本帮我们组建家庭
We've got a joke in our family that "This" Brought us together,
第二本帮我们还房贷
and "That" Paid for our apartment.
好吧
Ok.
但瑟琳的角色有点怪 伙计
But it must be a little weird for Celine, man.
她在书中的表现 不觉得吗
The way that she's in the book. No?
会吗 可能她已习以为常了
Why? I think she has gotten used to it.
第二本写得真香艳 伙计
But the second one is sexy, man.
男主角错过飞机后 他们就把窗户关上
When he misses the plane and they blackout the windows,
然后没日没夜地做爱
and have sex for days and days and days.
就像明天就是世界末日一样
Like there's no tomorrow.
你们真是那样吗
Did you guys actually do that?
是真的 对吧
You did that, huh?
你看过杰西的第三本书没
Have you read Jesse's third book?
事实上比前两本写得好
It's actually better than the first two.
反正写的时间
It certainly took longer
比前两本加起来都要长
to write than the first two put together.
我没看第三本 我老婆给我了
No, the third one I didn't read, I mean my wife gave it to me,
但我觉得有点长
but it's a just a little bit too long for me.
连书名也很长 叫什么来着
Even the title is long. What's the title?
《长年上演的小众话剧
"Temporary cast members of a long-running
中的临时演员们》
but little-seen production of a play called fleeting"
我说得没错吧
Well, exactly my point.
不止是你 其他人也觉得它太长了
You're not alone, everybody else thought it was too long.
这本书写得更好 更有野心
It is a better book, it's so much more ambitious.
他说什么
What was that?
他说 三本书他都喜欢
No, he says, he likes... he likes all the books.
真的
He does.
我喜欢这里 这里棒极了
I mean I love it here. This place is amazing,
番茄也棒极了
those tomatoes are so amazing.
闻起来都觉得好吃 真好闻
I can smell them, they smell so good.
是的 帕特里克对此引以为豪
Yeah. Patrick is very proud of them.
我知道这样想很蠢 不过…
I know it's stupid but...
当决定离开巴黎到这来时
When we were about to leave Paris,
其实我很担心
I was all nervous we were about to come here.
现在要走了 却又舍不得
And now we're about to leave and I do not wanna go.
- 为什么会担心  - 是啊 为什么
- Why were you nervous?  - Yes, why was that?
我不知道 这地方承载着
I do not know. this place is so full of
千百年的悲欢离合
thousands of years of myth and tragedies,
我害怕有不好的事要发生
and I thought something tragic was gonna happen.
弥诺陶洛斯：古希腊神话中人身牛头怪物
你怕弥诺陶洛斯会来吃你的小孩
You thought the Minotaur was going to eat your children.
是的
Yes.
没错
Exactly.
这些天来 我有了一个想法
All the time I've been here I've been working on this idea about
是关于一群大脑异常的人
a group of different people with all these brain abnormalities.
我想从他们的独特视角出发
So the book would be like a day in their life,
来观察他们日常生活中的一天
from all their unique points of view,
就比如有位老太太
Right? Like there's this older lady who has the condition that
她会沉浸在似曾相识的感觉当中
makes you feel like you're in a perpetual state of deja vu.
每一个经历过的场景
And every single experience she has,
她都会觉得似曾相识
she feels like she's had it before.
她有可能坐在这
I mean she could be sitting here with us
很正常地跟我们聊天
talking seemingly functional right?
其实她脑子里在想
And in her head she's thinking,
这话他刚刚不是说过了吗
didn't he already say that?
会不会我们昨天也在这
I mean, weren't we here yesterday?
展开了一模一样的谈话
Having this exact same conversation?
就像有即视感
So just like deja vu?
是的 不过更频繁
Yeah, except all the time.
她所接触过的每一样事物
That's the thing, right, everything she takes in.
一份早餐 一张报纸 一场电影
A breakfast, a newspaper, a movie.
她都认为自己早就经历过
She is convinced she's encountered it already.
这种情况真的存在吗
Is that a real condition?
是的 叫做持续性即视…
Yeah, it is called persistent Dejav...
确实存在 我不会拼而已
It's real but I can't pronounce it.
接着是截然相反的两个人
There are two other characters with facial recognition extremes.
一个二十年来从来都认不出自己的老婆
There is one guy and he can not recognize his wife for 20 years.
他看着镜子中的自己
He looks at himself in the mirror,
会感到陌生
and he feels disconnected with that man he's looking at.
另一个角色则刚好相反
And the other character is the opposite.
这位中年主妇有着
A middle-aged housewife with a categorical exacting memory
对人过目不忘的本领
of every face she has ever seen.
虽在大城市 对她而言却与小城镇无异
And she lives in a big city but to her it is a small town.
就比如有辆计程车经过 她就会想
Like a taxi drives past and she thinks,
那不就是三年前的圣诞节
"Oh that's the driver who dropped me off
孚日广场：巴黎最古老的广场
在孚日广场放下我的司机吗
at Place des Vosges three Christmases ago."
就比如看见有位老太太走在街上
Like some old lady, walking on the street,
她就会想 她是去年在地铁上
she thinks, "Oh! She sat two seats down from me
坐在我后两位的老太太
on the metro last year."
所以她对遇见的每个人
So everyone she meets, you know,
都感到亲密无间
to her feels intimate and connected.
我喜欢你说的第一个
Well, I'm like the first guy,
因为大多时候我也是见人就忘
I feel connected to nothing most of the time.
阿奇里斯 安娜 你们好
Hey! Achilleas! Anna! Hey guys.
看这孩子 他暑假过得比我们都要好
Look at this kid, he is having the best summer of us all.
所以你要说的就是这三个角色 对吗
So, you were saying these three characters, right?
不 这只是那一群人当中的三个角色
No. It's not just three characters, it's a whole group of people.
我现在也有一章是写
Like I'm working on a Chapter right now,
一个叫阿奇里斯的年轻希腊男子
about a young Greek man named Achilleas.
- 我吗  - 是以你命名的
- Me?  - Well, he's named after you.
这个人陷入了迷阵
And this guy is caught in a loop,
在他看来一切都是转瞬即逝的
all he sees is the transient nature of everything.
就像他看到这片海
Like he looks out to the sea, and he thinks of the day
他想到的是它干涸和堆满化石的一天
it's gonna be dry and littered with fossils.
怎么说呢 听上去有点做作
Well, I do not know. Sounds a little pretentious to me.
不 不会做作 我保证
No no no, it won't be pretentious, I promise, I promise.
会很有趣 真的很有趣
It's gonna be funny. Really funny.
他捡到一本书马上想到的是
He picks up a book and immediately wonders,
最后读到这本书的人会是谁
who's gonna be the last person to read this?
- 这有趣吗  - 有时候我也会那样想
- And that's funny?  - Sometimes I kind of think like that.
所以他不喜欢乳房啊 车啊 饮酒啊
Ok, so he does not get excited about
对这些都不感兴趣
tits, cars, booze, nothing?
- 一心只想着死亡  - 也不全是死亡
- Just thinks about death.  - Well, not so much death.
像变了一个人似的
It's like transformation, you know,
对于未来过于杞人忧天
like he is seeing too far in the future.
- 好吧  - 我喜欢这个想法
- Ok.  - I like this idea for a novel.
不过你应该加个像我一样的老头上去
But you should add a character of an old man like me.
一个连早餐吃过什么都会忘的人
A poor sapp who can't remember what he ate for breakfast,
但对于十四岁那年在珠儿酒吧
But still hear the song that was playing,
希拉·坎贝尔：八十年代美国女影星
看到希拉·坎贝尔半裸跳舞时
when Sheila Campbell danced topless
所听到的音乐记忆犹新
on the bar at Jurees when he was 14 years old.
这提议很不错
That would work.
这些人都在时间里迷失了 对吧
Ok. you have these people lost in time, right?
他们之间的联系在哪 是通过做爱吗
What is the connection? Are they gonna have sex?
难道不需要把他们联系到一起吗
Don't you need something like that?
他们并非迷失在时间里 而是感知出了问题
It's not time they have lost in, right? It's like, perception.
这样说吧
That's the deal,
我打算把整部小说设置在一部电影当中
I'm thinking of setting the whole novel at a movie.
每个角色都会跟
Like every character in some way
《码头风云》：马龙白兰度主演的奥斯卡获奖影片
《码头风云》这部电影产生一定的联系
comes into contact with the film "On the Waterfront".
看过《码头风云》没
Have you seen On the Waterfront?
《码头风云》吗
On the Waterfront?
白兰度演的吗
With Brando?
书的第一章发生于一九五四年的一个周末
The first chapter of the book is opening at a weekend
在时代广场
in Times Square in 1954.
有着持续性即视感的老太太
That old lady with perpetual deja vu
走去看日场放映
walks into the matinee screening,
但她却满脑子疑惑
except the whole time she's thinking,
我不是已经看过了吗
"Haven't I already seen this?"
另外一章发生在一九七九年
Yeah, and then in another chapter
巴黎的一个电影学习班里
is a 1979 Paris film studies class.
接下来会发生在一九九三年
Then we have a Kazan
慕尼黑的一场喀山回顾展里
retrospective in Munich in 1993.
这讲的就是时间 怎么不是时间呢
Well man, that is time. How is that not time?
确实与时间有关 但讲的更多的是感知
Yeah, it's time, but it's more perception.
- 你不喜欢吗  - 我怕你又写很长
- You don't like it?  - I think it's gonna be too long!
我喜欢 别听他的 做单车的懂什么
Well. I like it. Do not listen to him, he makes bicycles.
记得寄一份到我加勒的地址
Send it to me in Galles.
这是肯定的
Will do!
在法国番茄跟辣椒
In France we stuff the tomatoes with tomatoes,
会酿上不同的馅
and the peppers with peppers.
真的吗 我们这都酿同一种馅
Oh, really? Because we use the same stuffing for both.
这样你就能尝到馅糅合香草的味道
Because of the way it reacts with the leaves you can taste.
好吧
Ok.
瑟琳 别酿太满
Oh, and Celine, make sure you don't stuff them too much,
不然待会馅溢出烤炉
because of the way it overflows in the oven later.
会比较难清洁
It gets kind of nasty.
你做的很好 瑟琳
You're doing fine, Celine.
千万要记住 别听斯特凡诺斯的
And especially do not listen to Stefanos here.
他没做过这道菜
Because he has never made this dish before,
实际上他就没做过菜
or any other dish, for that matter.
别拿着刀吵架
Stop fighting with knives!
别这样 别拿着刀吵架
Stop it! Stop fighting with knives!
我们没有吵架 我们是在商量
We're not fighting, we are negotiating.
商量 你们管这叫商量
Negotiating. That's how you call it?
哇 带着刀的商量啊
Wow, négociation avec des couteaux!
完全正确
Exactement!
这是我们相处的方式
It is a system that we have.
看来你们找到了适合你们的方式
So you found the system that works for you.
我想这就叫磨合
I thought it was called having a "Relationship".
不过我喜欢你们的说法 很棒
But I like system, that's pretty good.
- 这可以了吧  - 可以了
- That's ready, right?  - That's ready.
你呢 你的相处方式是什么
Toi, c'est quoi ton system?
- 我是这个  - 不错嘛
- Celui-là.  - Pas mal.
我们以前也那样
We used to have that system.
别游太远
Not too far you guys!
我想借这顿饭机会
Alright, I just don't want to let this meal go by
跟在座各位说声谢谢
without just saying thank you to everyone.
特别是你 帕特里克
And especially you, Patrick.
这六周多亏有你的招待
we had no idea what we were getting into these last six weeks.
我在大学里收到一份邀约
A letter arrives from the university
一位伟大的作家邀请我们
inviting us to the Southern Peloponnese of Greece
到他希腊南伯罗奔尼萨的旅舍去度假
to the guesthouse of a great writer.
好啊 为什么拒绝
Sure! Why not?
今天早上在机场
And then at the airport earlier today.
汉克对我说
Hank turns to me and he says that
这是他度过最棒的暑假
this has been the greatest summer of his life.
我也一样 谢谢你 帕特里克
And I have to say the same, so thank you, Patrick!
我不仅要敬你为我和我的家人所做的一切
And not just for what you done for me and my family,
还要敬你一直以来的慷慨奉献
But for all the ways that you have given back, alright?
敬帕特里克
To Patrick!
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you, thank you, thank you,
当我第一次在机场看见你
you know when I first saw you at the airport.
我心想 这男的穿成这样
I thought, no way, a man dressed like that
怎么可能是个作家
could be a man of letters.
但现在我总算找出原因了
But now. I think I've learned your secret,
在过去十年里也出现过许多优秀的作家
we've had many great writers over the past decade,
但没有一位的妻子比作家本身还要有意思
but never one who had a partner more interesting than themselves.
谁说不是呢
I'm telling you.
瑟琳 感谢你和你的女儿
And Celine, it's been so great to
为这里带来了无限的生机
have you and your daughters' wonderful vitality around here.
同时也很高兴能为你引见
And I'm so happy you were able to meet
我的好朋友娜塔莉
my dear friend Natalia.
她的丈夫伊莱亚斯跟我情同手足
Whose husband Elias was like a brother to me.
对上校的事我感到很抱歉
I'm so sorry about the Colonel.
- 我说的是上次…  - 是我的错
- I mean the early...  - I should... It was my fault.
我跟安娜也要感谢这次暑假邀约
Thanks for including Anna and me this summer.
因为他平常只会让我去工作
Because you know he usually puts me to work.
但我把安娜带来时
But when I bring Anna,
他让我坐在大人桌上
he let me sit at the table of the grown-ups.
欢迎来到大人桌
Welcome to the grown-up's table!
你们俩在一起多久了
How long have you two been together?
从上个暑假到现在
Since last summer.
我们一年前在这里邂逅
We met one year ago here,
那是在我要回雅典之前
in my last days with Grandpa,
陪伴爷爷的最后几天
before I had to go back to Athens.
是的 我们在闭幕晚会上相遇
Yes, we met at my closing night cast party.
那时候我在剧院演莎翁的戏
I was doing Shakespeare in the theater.
你演什么角色
Who did you play?
我演《冬天的故事》里的潘狄塔
I was Perdita. The winter's tale.
她演得很好
She was fantastic.
帕特里克 记得我们看的那次吗
Remember, Patrick, we went to there?
潘狄塔 当你跳舞时
Perdita, "When you do dance,
我希望你是浩淼海洋中的一道波浪
I wish you a wave o' th' sea,
这样就已足够
that you might ever do Nothing but that."
你演得
The way you just performed,
比剧中那小伙子好多了
that was much better than the guy in the play.
人们至今还对那部剧津津乐道
People are still talking about that production.
但更棒的在宴会后 那是我俩头次见面
But the after-party was even better, it was when we met.
对 我开着老款的BSA型摩托车
Yeah, I had an old BSA motorcycle.
不错
Nice.
整晚我们都在兜风
So... we drove around all night,
最后我们开回剧院
and then I had to drive her back to the theater,
去拿她的东西
to get her stuff.
那时天已经蒙蒙亮了
And it was the dawn.
我永远忘不了那一刻
And I'll never forget it.
那是个露天剧场 可容纳一万两千人
It was outdoors and it seats 12000 people,
空空荡荡的
and it was now completely empty.
她径直走到最后一排坐下
And she was sitting way up in the back row.
所以 我登上舞台
So... I went up on stage
低声对她说
and whispered to her.
声音的传播好奇妙
The acoustics there are incredible.
我先看到他的嘴在动
I could see his mouth move and then 3 seconds later,
三秒后我才听到他的声音
I could hear his voice in my ear.
他说的什么
What did he say?
- 好  - 好
- OK!  - Right.
小秘密
It is private.
然后她飞回巴黎住些日子
And then she had to fly back to Paris a couple of days later.
你们怎么联络呢
How did you keep in touch?
我们用视频聊天
We Skyped.
几乎天天聊
Pretty much every day since then.
我们睡觉时
And we are in bed,
必然会把电脑放在枕边
we have a thing of putting our laptop by the pillow,
看着对方一起入睡
and... falling asleep together
听着又新鲜又浪漫
Oh that's the new romance.
等醒来 屏幕基本都定格在
And when I wake up the screen is usually frozen
一些很滑稽的姿势 就像这样
and Anna's face is in some funny position like...
我来问个问题
Can I ask you a question?
你们视频聊天时
When you guys Skype
有点小疯狂的事情没有
Do you, you know... do you go a little crazy?
天 你的节操呢
My God! You're being so vulgar!
这无关什么节操
No, nothing to vulgar.
我是个对虚拟世界比较感性趣的
I'm just being a amateur anthropologist
只停留在理论水平的业余人类学家
who is interested in the virtual world on a theoretical level.
你倒成了人类学家了
Now you're an anthropologist.
没错 题目是未来的性爱
Yes, the sex of the near future.
我这不是胡扯
And I'm not making this up but it's
将来会在你的生殖器里放入个装置
gonna be just like plugging in something in your genitals.
冒犯了 可以根据你的需要
I'm sorry. And you can have sexual intercourse
来选择跟谁性交
with anyone of your choice.
专门为你定制
You'll be able to programme in all your preferences.
满足你的要求
You'll be able to type in exactly what you want.
比如让玛丽莲·梦露 在你耳边轻语
Marilyn Monroe to whisper in your ear.
听起来超赞 没错
I might like that! Yes!
为什么不呢
I mean... Why not?
越来越多的人们
More and more of our
把时间放到了虚拟世界上
experiences are taking place in the virtual world.
是的
Yeah...
你是作家 如果有一天电脑能写出
And you're a writer. How are you gonna feel when
比战争与和平还好的书 你会怎么想
Computers can write a better book than 'War and Peace'
不会有那一天的
That will never happen.
我想现在唯一的问题是什么时候会发生
I think the only question is when it's going to happen.
我想与卡斯特罗的感觉差不多
I think I will probably feel about the same way as Kasparov
记得吧
you remember, all those
所有那些棋手都不能战胜的
chess players felt when they could no compete
超级电脑
with that big-ass computer...
- 深蓝  - 对对 就是那个
- The big blue.  - Right, right.
最初大家都认为
Remember at first thought
电脑不能战胜人类
nobody thought a computer could ever beat our best.
机器没有人类那妙不可言的天资
A machine lacks that ineffable human instinct.
现在我们却输得一塌糊涂
You know and now we can't even compete.
我看过一篇文章
I saw a documentary where
上面说他们用小白鼠做了个实验
they were doing an experiment on a lab rat.
将它身上连了个开关
And..he was wired up and
打开开关它就能高潮
could push a switch and have an orgasm,
然后这个可怜的小家伙
and so, the scientists were
让科学家们一顿爆笑
sort of laughing at this pathetic little creature.
它不吃不喝 就不停的触摸开关
While it ignores food and water and didn't do anything else.
最后它就这么死了
And eventually it just died.
我觉得这就是
I mean, I think that's the
人类的未来 就像…
future of humanity, you know? Just...
爽到死
and die!
有可能吧
Well, maybe so
每代人都认为
but every generation believes
自己见证了世界末日
that they're witnessing the end of the world.
但
But...
看我 不还活得好好的
I feel that I'm actually living it.
好 我问个问题 帕特里克
Ok I have a question for you Patrick.
许多人都这样觉得
I think a lot of people are feeling that way... you know
人们都着迷于享乐
We are like this kind of pleasure-obsessed
腐蚀于性爱 不断追求物质
porn-addled Materialist.
将人性深埋于科技的土壤中
Seeding our humanity to technology
而这时 计算机正变得拥有感情
At the same moment that computers are becoming sentient.
对吧 所以我的问题是
Right? So what my question is,
这种自觉到底从何而来
is this notion of 'self' to begin with.
德尔斐阿波罗神庙门前
Well it's written over
刻着这么几个字
the portals of the temple of Apollo at Delhi
就是“Γνώθι σ' αυτόν”[希腊语]
it says"Gnothi seauton"
意思是“认识你自己”
Which means "Know thyself"
但现在基本全自动化了
Yes but we are kind of 99% automated already.
而性格这种属于自觉的东西
No our personality or this thing we think of as ourselves.
其实只占大脑运作的一小部分
It is only a tiny fraction of what the brain is doing.
身体绝大多数的机能又都是自行运转的
Most of these automated body functions.
那么自觉到底根植于何处呢
So then is what is it we're actually seeding?
这种自觉的概念
Now, if this notion of self
如果只占那么一丁点的话
is such a small percentage of usage
为何我总能听到关于它的话题呢
How come I always hear so much about it?
就像我的小鸡鸡
Well it's just like my penis.
不是说它有多大
I mean it's not that big
虽然只是身体的一小部分
it is a small part of myself
但需要很多关照
But it needs a lot of attention.
他的也是
His too!
你们是怎么认识的
And how did you two meet?
你不知道吗
You do not know?
怎么
What?
去读读杰西的书
Well, you have to read Jesse's books.
想知道跟我做爱什么感觉
Yeah, especially if you want to know
就去仔细读读 快去读读
exactly what it is like to have sex with me, read away!
赶快去读
Read away!
不好意思 斯特凡诺斯
Excuse me, Stefanos.
我意思是那肯定是本好书
I mean it's well written.
对
Yeah
我们十八年前相识
We met about 18 years ago and we kind of,
相互之间有一点感觉
sort of fell in love a little bit.
然后 我们失去了联系
and... then we lost track of each other
大概十年后 我们又遇见了
And a decade later, we ran into each other.
不 不是遇见 小笨熊
No, no, no ... we did not run into each other, sweetie bear
你写的那本书 灵感来自我们相遇
You wrote a book inspired by our meeting...
我读了之后 决定去找他
And I read about it and went to look for him.
好浪漫
That's pretty romantic.
没有 没有
Not really, not really, not really.
他没说他结婚了
He neglects to mention that he was married,
- 也没说有了孩子  - 那是细节
- had a kid...  - Details! Details!
想起来真是灾难
Yeah that part was a disaster!
谈不上吧 这没办法避免
It wasn't a disaster, it was inevitable.
第一次没有带套
And the first time that we had sex without a condom.
一下生了对双胞胎 我就被拖下水了
Twins! And have been chained to the sink ever since...
很遗憾
Sorry to say that.
没这么糟吧
It's not that bad is it?
你家闺女多漂亮
The girls are so beautiful.
又那么可爱
They are cute.
还是有好的方面 对吧
Ok... no, no, it has some upsides.  Ok.
让我教教你 安娜 怎样抓住男人的心
Let me tell you right now, Anna, how to keep a man
玩愚蠢的小游戏时 得处处让着他们
You got to let them win at all the silly little games
- 老天  - 他们喜欢
- Oh God!  - they like...
我们俩认识的第一晚 一起玩弹球
When I met Jessy the first night we were playing pinball.
- 当然是我赢了  - 你听到的
- And of course I was winning.  - What you are hearing is the
是我们俩恋爱关系里 最低级的谎言
foundational lie to our entire relationship ...
最后一刻
And at the last minute I let the
- 我让球这样从中间过去  - 不对
- ball go down in the middle.  - It is... It is, no.
- 这才能帮他们建立信心  - 玩什么都行
- It builds their confidence,  - She can't beat me at one game,
- 如果不让他们赢  - 不是所有游戏
- if I didn't let him win it every game,  - not any game...
我们就不能上床
We would never have sex.
我不得不说
I mean... I'm sorry to say
他是隐性大男子主义者
all this but he's actually a closet macho.
就想娶个胸大无脑的老婆
He dreams of having a bimbo for a wife.
- 那是我最大的梦想  - 做梦吧
- It is my greatest aspiration.  - Dreams!
那么
So...
怎么
Yes?
你是个作家吗
So you're a writer?
是呀
Yeah, yeah... sure.
那你写的是书吗
So you write like... books?
我只写了几本
I've written a few, sure.
人家以前从没遇到过作家
Wow... I've never met a writer before.
你肯定聪明极了
You must be really smart.
有时人家累了
You know... I can't even
甚至连自己的名字也写不好
write my own name sometimes when I'm tired.
你喜欢哪种书呢
What kind of books do you like?
人家喜欢故事里充满了
Well I like stories with a meaning behind it,
美丽的爱情
like a really beautiful love story.
没错
Oh sure yes!
我曾读过一本书叫《罗密欧和…
You know... I read this book once... Romeo and...
朱莉叶
Juliet
对呀
Yeah!
你也看过吗
Wow! You know it?
挺棒的 但其实那是出戏剧
It's very good. It's a play, actually.
那不是书 是戏剧
It is not a book, a play.
人家以为那本书是电影改编的呢
Oh I thought it was a book based on the movie.
- 不 是戏剧  - 原来是戏剧呀
- No, no, a play  - Ok, it was a play, wow!
其实人家没有读完
Well, actually I did not read the whole thing
因为人家
because sometimes I have to
有读杂志的习惯
keep up and read these magazines
好了解大家都在做什么
To know exactly what's going on in all those peoples' lives.
- 这很重要  - 你这么聪明
- Well that is important.  - Ok you are very, very smart.
我想你的下面也一定很厉害
And I bet you have a gigantic penis.
怎么我就这么爱这个女人
Why am I finding myself so attracted to this woman?!
这是男子主义有趣的一面
And that's the funny part of it.
而糟糕的一面是
The not so funny part of the
今天我们去机场送亨利
closet macho, ok, is that today after we drop Henry off,
之后他告诉我
He tells me that
即使我有一份非常理想的工作
even though I have an offer for an amazing job,
他还是想我放弃并跟他去芝加哥
He wants me to throw it away and move to Chicago.
我没这么说
That's not what I said,
- 我说我很想他  - 没错 这样我们
- I said I missed him.  - Yes, so we can babysit
- 你可以  - 每隔一周都可替他的前妻
- You were expressing something  - every other weekend for
- 表达你的观点 我也一样  - 照顾孩子
- you felt conflicted about and I did the same.  - his ex-wife.
我以为我已经融入你的生活
I thought I was in a relationship.
你们停一停 今天跟亨利道别
Hey, you guys stop it, It must have
很不容易 对吧
been so hard to saying goodbye to Henry today, right?
- 没错  - 我想他也是个很聪明的小家伙
- Yeah, of course.  - And I mean he is such an amazing kid.
我还想和他成为搭档一起下棋
Yeah... I'll rate him as my chess partner
等到斯特凡诺斯和我分手
When Stefanos and I split up,
我要申请唯一监护权
I am getting full custody
这一时半会到不成问题
Well that's okay for a while
因为我和我二十岁的女友
because me and my 20-year-old girlfriend
还有得折腾呢
will be a little bit preoccupied.
- 我爱男人  - 我爱你
- Oh I love man.  - And I love you.
我讲个我老公喜欢的故事
Ok... I have a story that my husband here loves.
这个故事讲述了
And that's gonna tell you everything about
男性与女性不同的特质
masculine and feminine, right?
准备好了吗
Ok, ready?
我妈妈曾经是名护士
My mom used to be a nurse so she
当病人从昏迷中醒来 她总是陪在旁边
was there when people were coming out of the coma.
认真听 这故事很有趣
Listen, it's an interesting story.
- 我在听  - 并且告诉病人
- I'm listening.  - So she was the one to tell them...
我的名字叫凯瑟琳娜 你刚从昏迷中醒来
Hi... My name is Catherina you're coming out of a coma.
你遇到了严重的交通事故
You've been in a really bad automobile accident.
你会好起来的
You're gonna be okay.
你会没事的 这样之类的话
You're gonne be fine and, you know, stuff like that
她说 每个女人醒来的第一件事
She said  that every woman
第一件 第一反应就是
the very first thing, the first reaction she would have
问身边的人
Would be to ask to ask about everyone else:
我的孩子有事吗
how are my kids?
我的丈夫有事吗 有其他人受伤吗
How is my husband? Is anyone else hurt?
而男人们 无一例外
Every man with no exception, when they
当他们被这样告知 第一反应是什么呢
were told all this, what was the first thing they did?
低头看看自己老二
Looked down on their cock.
得先确定它还在那里
You know what? You got to make sure it's still there.
它还好用吧
You got to make sure it's still working.
- 必须的  - 还能一柱擎天
- You have to!  - Alive and kicking!
最后
Yeah, yeah, and eventually
他们回过神来 才想起问问他们的孩子
they come around to asking about their kids
或其他人
or about someone else that might
有没有受伤 这样
have accidentally been killed, and stuff like that.
不是有句话吗 叫老二的事最重要
Does not say it all? Penis first and the rest of the world.
老二 老二
Penis! Penis!
你们能从纯粹的性别角度解释
But if you can explain it on strictly gender terms
你们为什么 或者说为什么女人要浪费时间
why do you, or why does any woman waste time
不厌其烦的尝试改变一个男人呢
getting mad at or bother to trying to change a man?
没错 这是生物学 到底是什么问题呢
Exactly! It's all biology. What is the problem?
你太会转移话题了
And you are so, so good at turnings things around ...
- 不 我只是想说  - 他是个天才
- NO... I'm just trying to say that.  - He is a genius.
这就叫鸡蛋里面挑骨头
it's like getting pissed at frog for being green.
- 没错  - 听了这么久
- Yes! Exactly!  - Hearing all this,
我就想 天长地久相爱
I wonder if this idea of a love
这种事还和我们有关吗
affair that lasts forever is still relevant to us?
都知道
I mean we know that we are
我们最终会分开
going to break up eventually.
毫无疑问
Definitely.
- 你的父母还在一起吗  - 没有
- Are your parents are still together?  - No way.
没有 那你的呢
No and what about yours?
在一起 但他们可以离婚
They are, but they could divorced.
他们有钱的话
I think if they had more money,
估计早就离了
they would not still be together.
老天 你们都太实际了
God, you guys are so practical,
我真是生错了年代
I was born into the wrong generation.
我曾祖母
My grandmother's mother
在她临终前
wrote to our whole family
留下了二十六页的长信
a 26-page letter from her deathbed
她花了三页去说
and she spent three pages
她为一部戏设计的服装
on the costume she did for a play...
而仅用一段来说她的丈夫
and only one paragraph on her husband.
她也是演员吗
Was she an actress too?
不 她是个
No... she was...a...
英语“女裁缝”怎么说
Comment on dit " couturière "?
女裁缝
Seamstress.
她有很多
And she had all these
不错的朋友 而关于我曾祖父
wonderful friends and about my great-grandfather
她仅提到三件事
She mentioned three events:
他去参战 因为他的工作搬家
He went to war, we moved because of his job
他死了
And he died.
她的忠告是
Her big advice was
不要在浪漫的爱情上消耗太多
not to be too consumed with romantic love
友谊和工作
Friendships and work, she said,
才给我带来真正的快乐
brought to her the most happiness.
我再同意不过了
I could not agree more,
我们就是被这样教育长大的 对吧
I mean that's the thing that fucks us up right?
只有这种精神伴侣
This idea of a soul mate of someone
才能让我们变得完整
who would come to complete us
帮助我们承担生活中的问题
and save us from having to take care of ourselves.
对于斯特凡诺斯 我将标准降得非常低
With Stefanos, I set the bar extremely low
我知道他做不到我的要求
I know he is not gonna meet any of my needs
太难了
Definitely not.
那你的祖母呢 她是你的精神伴侣吗
So what about Grandma? Was she your soul mate?
说得好听 不过
Sounds appealing but actually
你祖母其实更加理性一些
your grandmother was more rational than that.
她很独立 也这样要求我
She took cared of herself and asked me to do the same.
让我们有足够的空间 协商一致
With plenty of room to meet in the middle.
听起来很理想
Yeah, that sounds ideal
那确实很理想
That's is, actually.
很显然 我妻子今天不在这
But it must be obvious that my wife is not here today.
我们从来不是一个人
We were never one person,
是两个独立的人 我们也很喜欢这样
always two, we preferred it that way.
真是美丽的故事
That is so beautiful.
我认为我的丈夫
I think my husband is
总是想吞并我
always trying to almost colonize me, you know
我吞并你吗
I colonize you?
是的 但我也在吞并你 亲爱的
Yes but I colonize you, too, darling.
好吧
Well ... Ok.
但在最后的时日
But at the end of the day
你会发现
It's not the love of one
你不是爱着一个人 而是爱着这种生活
other person that matters it's the love of life.
那太好了 帕特里克
That's good to know, Patrick,
因为生活我能自己掌控
because life I can handle.
而阿里阿德涅
Ariadni, on the other hand,
我们都知道希腊出悲剧 对吧
We all know that the Greeks invented tragedy, right?
而且她还来自玛尼
and on top of that it stems
狂躁这个词就来源于此地
from the original Mani, which is short for Mania.
对了 如果今晚我们去不了旅馆
Hey, guys if we can not make that hotel
你们能退掉它或你们自己去住吗
room tonight could you get a refund or use it yourself?
不 我们退不了款
No... we do not get a refund.
你们不想住吗
Are you trying to get out of it?
不是 这份礼物太棒了
No, it's such a great gift you've given us.
但还要打行李
But I'm so stressed getting.
还有女孩们 压力太大
all the packing ready, with the girls...
- 不 不  - 这样吧
- No, no...  - We made a deal guys.
我们帮你看孩子 你们好好享受
We will watch the kids, you're gonna love it.
- 慢慢走去旅馆  - 会非常棒的
- It's a fantastic walk to  - It's really really good.
- 那感觉非常美妙 你们不会后悔的  - 没错
- the hotel You won't regret it.  - It is.
不去的话 我们可是会生气的
And we would be very offended if you don't go.
好吧
Ok...
谢谢你们
Thank you.
当我想起我的丈夫
Well... when I think of my husband,
我非常想念
what I miss the most about him
夜晚他躺在我身边的感觉
is the way he used to lie down next to me at night.
有时他会把胳膊横在我的胸前
Sometimes his arm would stretch along my chest,
我动不了 甚至要憋住呼吸
and I could not move, I... I even held my breath.
但我感到 安心
But I felt safe
完整
Complete.
我也想念
And... I miss the way
他走在街上吹着口哨的样子
he was whistling walking down the street.
每次做什么我都会想他怎么做
And every time I do something I think of what he would say,
天冷了 要披上围巾
when it's cold today, wear a scarf.
但是之后 我渐渐忘却细节
But lately I've been forgetting little things.
记忆在不断褪色 我开始忘记他
It's sort of fading and I'm starting to forget him.
这就像
And it's like ...
我又失去了他
like losing him again.
所以有时 我努力回想
So sometimes I make myself remember
他脸庞的每一处
every detail of his face.
眼睛的颜色 唇齿的样子
The exact color of his eyes, his lips, his teeth,
他的皮肤和头发的触感
the texture of his skin, his hair.
这一切记忆都随着时间流走了
That was all gone by the time he went.
但有时 偶尔 只是偶尔
And sometimes... not always, but sometimes,
我能非常清楚的看到他
I can actually see him.
就好像拨开云雾 他就在那里
It's as if a cloud moves away and there he is.
我几乎能碰到他
And I could almost touch him.
突然 真实回到了眼前
But then... the real world rushes in.
他再次消失了
And he vanishes again.
曾几何时 每天早晨
For a while, I did this every morning,
天刚亮的时候 我都会看到他
when the sun was not too bright outside.
可不知为何 他又会消失在阳光下
But the sun somehow makes him vanish.
他出现又消失
And he appears and he disappears,
像日出和日落
like a sunrise and a sunset.
一切都那么短暂
Anything, so ephemeral.
正如我们的生活
It's just like our life.
我们出现又消失
We appear and we disappear.
我们对有些人来说很重要
And we are so important to some,
可我们又只是擦肩而过
but we are just... passing through.
敬 擦肩而过
To "passing through"
To "Passing through"
终于 他在窗户的倒映下看清了自己的脸
And eventually he catches his face in the window's reflection
他意识到自己已不再是那个9岁的小男孩了
And he realizes he's no longer a 9 year old boy.
对吧 他突然之间变老了 有了胡子
Right? He's suddenly old, he's got a beard
- 眼睛里水雾缭绕  - 确实让人难过
- and his eyes are watery  - This one seems sad
开始我还以为你要给我讲故事
At first I thought you were going to tell me a story
就是关于一个人臆想出一个朋友的那个
about a guy that has an imaginary friend
哪个
Which one?
他五十多岁的时候 那个虚拟朋友又出现了
When in his 50s, the imaginary  friend shows up again.
和一只蜂鸟一起
With the hummingbird?
- 没错 就是这个  - 你喜欢吗
- Yes, that!  - You liked that one?
很有趣
It's funny.
还记得你让我看过的那封信吗
Remember that letter
你二十岁时写给
that you let me read that you wrote
四十岁的自己的那封信
when you were 20 to yourself at 40.
当然 我还记得第一句话
Yes, I remember the first sentence:
亲爱的四十岁的杰西 但愿你没有离婚
Dear 40-year-old Jesse, I hope you're not divorced
我不记得有这部分了
No I did not even remember that part,
我是想说那封信里还提到别的事情
I meant to all the other things in that letter
你还是那个你 我们总觉得自己会成长
You're the same guy, I mean, we always think that we are evolving
可我们并无力改变多少
But we can not change that much
- 你知道我是怎样看待我的变化的  - 怎样
- You know how I think I've changed the most.  - How?
我年轻的时候总希望时间可以过得快一点
When I was younger I just wanted time to speed up.
为什么
Why?
因为那样 我就可以做我自己
So I can be on my own, so I can be free from my parents
摆脱掉家长和学校的一切束缚
and school and all that shit, you know,
我希望自己闭上眼 一睁眼就变成了成年人
I just wanted to close my eyes and wake up and be an adult
现在一切都如我所愿成为现实
And now I can feel that that happened
我却希望时间能停下来
and I want everything to slow down.
很奇怪 在我的一生当中
It's strange I've always had
这种感觉始终挥之不去
this feeling no matter where I am in my life.
既像是真实存在 又仿佛南柯一梦
That it's either a memory or a dream.
我知道你一直有这种感觉
I know you've always thought that.
我也是 就好像 这真的是我的人生吗
Me too, it's like is this really my life?
现在这一切都正在发生吗
Like is it happening, right now?
- 就是这样  - 我知道
- It is.  - I know!
每一年 我都会感受到
Every year I just seem to get
更大的压力和打击
a little bit more humbled and more overwhelmed
那些事情我从来搞不明白
about all things I'm never gonna know or understand
这就是我一直在告诫你的
That's what I keep telling you:
你一无所知
You know nothing.
我知道 我已经醒悟了
I know, I know! I'm coming around!
其实 一无所知并没有你想象的那么糟糕
But not knowing is not so bad.
我是说
I mean...
关键是要不断发现 寻找
The point is to be looking, searching,
保持如饥似渴的状态
to stay hungry, right?
没错 我只是希望能变得简单一点
That's true... I just wish it was a little easier.
什么意思
How do you mean?
你知道的 就是保持一定的热情
Just to maintain a certain level of passion, you know.
所有的一切都那么顺理成章
I mean, it used to come so naturally.
记得我年轻的时候 我的一群作家朋友们
Remember when I was younger, me and all my writer friends.
我们可以感觉到自己在做的是重要的事情
We like.. we just felt like were doing something important.
你知道吗 就好像是属于我们的时代
You know? Like this was our time.
可他们都是些骄傲自大的小子 对吗
But they were all a bunch of arrogant little pricks, right?
不 好吧 也许吧 我也不知道
No! Alright, maybe... I dunno...
我们长大后就渐渐失去了
we just grew out of all this energy,
当初的热情 创造力和雄心壮志
all this creativity or whatever ambitions people had.
我觉得人还是应该年少轻狂些才好
I think you gotta be a little deluded to stay motivated.
年轻人都是这样 不停地把自己和别人比较
Young men have this thing about comparing themselves all the time.
他们有很多自我评判的准绳
They have all these signposts they judge themselves by.
你以前也是这样
You used to do that all the time!
我怎么了 你什么意思
Do what? What do you mean?
像巴尔扎克十七岁创作出这部作品
It's like Balzac wrote this by 17,
而斯科特 ·菲茨杰拉德三十岁才写出来
F. Scott Fitzgerald did this by 30.
巴尔扎克每天早餐前创作一部作品
And Balzac wrote a book before breakfast everyday.
是的 可是女人们并不这么想
Yeah, but women do not think that way as much.
你这么认为吗
You don't think so?
我们只是没什么可比的罢了
We have much less to compare ourselves to, maybe.
大多数有所成就的女人
Most women who achieve anything in life.
在你第一次听说她们时 都已经五十多岁了
the first time you hear about them, they're in their 50s.
因为在这以前 对女人来说
because it is was so hard
想要得到一定的社会地位实在是太难了
for them to get any recognitions before then.
她们要么苦苦奋斗了三十年
They struggled for 30 years
要么就是在能做自己想做的事之前
or they raised kids and were stranded at home
都被困在家里 相夫教子
before they could do what they want.
你知道吗 这其实也算是一种解放
Actually you know what? It's kind of freeing.
我们不用每天忙着去和马丁·路德·金
We don't have to spend our lives
圣雄甘地 托尔斯泰这些人去比较
comparing ourselves to Martin Luther King, Ghandi, Tolstoy.
那圣女贞德呢
What about Joan of Arc?
我是说 她一个小姑娘却拯救了法国
I mean... she was a teenager and she saved France.
谁愿意做圣女贞德 忘记法国吧
Who wants to be Joan of Arc? Forget France.
她被绑在火刑柱上活活烧死 还是处女呢
She was burned at the stake, and a virgin!
我可不想这样 好吗 多伟大的情操
Ok? Nothing I aspire to. What a great achievement!
- 天哪  - 怎么了  - 没什么
- Oh God...  - What?  - No, nothing.
- 怎么了  - 这太奇怪了
- What?  - This is so weird.
- 什么意思  - 就像这样 我们边走边聊
- What do you mean?  - Just this, us walking, having a conversation.
讨论一切和饮食工作无关的话题
About something else than scheduling food, work.
自从为一些鸡毛蒜皮的事劳心后
I mean how long has it been
我们确实很久没有像现在这样了
since we were wondering around bullshiting
我听到了什么 你能听到吗
Do you hear what I hear?
- 大海的声音吗  - 不
- The sea?  - No.
什么 我知道了 没琐事牵绊的声音
What? Oh! No small feat.
没有什么被推翻 没有什么需要清理
Nothing being knocked over, nothing we have clean up.
也没有什么不公正的事情发生
Nothing injustices being done.
对啊 上一次是什么时候呢
Yeah, so when was the last time?
当我们无处可去的时候
When we had nowhere to be?
是啊 还记得我们在卢森堡公园吗
Yeah. Remember walking around the Luxembourg Gardens?
我在混凝土乒乓球桌上把你打得落花流水
I used to kick your ass in ping-pong on those concrete tables
恭喜你 竟然打赢了个怀着双胞胎的孕妇
Congrats! You beat a woman pregnant with twins!
真够男人的
Such a gentleman.
这总比输给一个怀着双胞胎的孕妇要好
It is better than losing to a pregnant woman with twins!
没错 天哪
Yes... O God!
你知道我在想什么吗 我在想
You know what I think? I think
从我们离开父母的那一刻起
it's from the time we leave our parents' house,
直到我们有了孩子
until we have kids, that's the only time
只有那时 你的生活是完全属于你自己的
that your life is completely your own.
那种日子大概过了十年 真的很好
I think I had about a decade of that, it was great, it was like,
就像是一次漫长的流浪 每一天
just like one long flowing, a day,
一星期 一年 都没有太大的区别
a week, a year, there wasn't much difference
不是 我过去总是把时间
No... I know, I used to keep track of time
花在工作和男朋友们的身上
through jobs and boyfriends and stuff like that.
现在我却可以说出
Now I can tell you
在过去的七年中
every detail of the past seven years
孩子们身上发生过的每一件小事
based on what was happening in the girls' lives
好吧 没错
Yeah...right... totally.
- 你也是吗  - 是的
- You do that too?  - Yes,
我是说 如果真的把时间划分开
if, I mean, time is demarcated now
不 真不敢相信 你竟然也记得
No, I'm just surprised you do that too
好吧 来个小测验
Ok... quick test
二〇〇九年八月
August 2009.
来吧 考考你 那时发生了什么
No, come on! It's a quick one. What was happening?
二〇〇九年八月 我们在和你父母度假
August 2009, we were on vacation with your parents.
妮娜先起了水痘 紧接着就是艾拉
Nina got the chickenpox first and quickly followed by Ella
- 真没想到  - 可以奖励我一颗五角星了吗
- I am so impressed.  - So do I get a gold star?
可以考虑
Maybe.
- 我能问你一个问题吗  - 当然了
- Hey... can I ask you a question?  - Sure.
如果我们今天第一次在火车上邂逅
If we were meeting for the first time today on a train,
你会被我吸引吗
would you find me attractive?
- 当然了  - 不 我是说我现在这个样子
- Of course.  - No, but really right now as I am
你会开始和我搭讪吗
Would you start talking to me?
你会邀请我和你一起下火车吗
Would you ask me to get off the train with you?
你的这些问题都是些假设
I mean you're asking a theoretical question.
我只想知道我的人生会是怎样
I mean what would my life-situation be?
从理论上来讲 它不会欺骗你吗
Technically, it would not be cheating on you?
- 你为什么不直接说会被我吸引  - 我说了
- Ok, why can not you just say yes?  - I did, I said, of course.
我只是想来点浪漫的 可是全被你破坏了
I wanted to say something romantic and you blew it, ok?
好吧 如果我在火车上看到你
Ok, ok... if I saw you on a train
听着 我的眼神会被你吸引
Ok, listen, I would lock eyes with you ..
之后 我会慢慢向你走来 对你说
and then I would walk right up to you and say
宝贝 你让我变成了
Hey baby, you are making me
一只在情欲里挣扎的山羊
as horny as a billy goat in a pepper patch.
住口 你太恶心了
Stop! That's disgusting!
不 事实上是你没有通过测试
No! The truth is that you failed the test and the fact is
而且你也不会在火车上和我搭讪
that you would not pick me up on the train.
你甚至都不会看我一眼
You would not even notice me,
一个肥臀还脱发的中年母亲
a fat-ass, middle-aged mom losing her hair
好了
Ok...
- 是啊 那才是我  - 这都是你逼我的
- Yes, that's me.  - You set me up to fail.
- 你逼的  - 对 对 没错
- You did.  - Ok, true.
可在现实世界里 小秃 那一天
But in the real world, baldy, Ok, on game day, when it mattered,
我确实在火车上和你搭讪了
I did, talk to you on the train,
我确实那样做了 那是我做过的最正确的事
I did that and it was the best thing I ever did.
是吗 看看那些山羊 你们好啊
Really? Look at the goats. Hello!
你知道 这可不是个好问题
You know that is not even a good question.
真正的问题是如果我邀请你和我一起下车
The real question would be if I did ask you to get off the train.
- 是啊  - 你会和我下车吗
- Yeah...  - Would you get off with me?
不 当然不会了 还有人在等我呢
No, of course not, I have people waiting for me.
你知道的 一只四十一岁还在发情的雄性山羊
You know, and a 41-year-old horny billy goat
太吓人了 我能起一身鸡皮疙瘩 救命啊
How creepy! I'm creeped out right now. Help!
救命啊[希腊语]
Βοήθεια
真不敢相信 我都四十一了
I can not believe I'm 41.
我也不敢相信 你竟然都这么老了
Yeah, me neither. You've gotten so old.
我没想过自己会和一个四十多岁的人睡在一起
Never thought I would ever sleep with anyone over 40
是啊
Yeah...
你知道吗
Actually you know what?
你是和我睡过的人当中年纪最大的一个
You are the oldest guy I've ever slept with.
- 这样啊  - 是真的
- That is something  - That's true.
我知道 不过我可不是你拒绝的最老的家伙
I know, but I'm not the oldest guy you've ever blown
- 什么  - 那次在华沙的会议
- What!  - That conference in Warsaw.
- 什么会议  - 瓦文萨
- What conference?  - Lech Walesa.
瓦文萨 你在说什么呢
Lech Walesa! Oh what are you talking about?
没关系 那都是我们在一起以前的事了
It's ok, it was before we're together
没什么不敢承认的 我还记得你提起过他
You can admit it. I can remember the way you talked about him.
他是如何让你打开心扉
How he opened your heart,
你明确地拒绝了他
you definitely blew him.
好吧 你真是疯了
Ok... you're really crazy!
那是戈尔巴乔夫
That was Gorbachev.
好吧 你这个地理不通
Ok? Geographically challenged,
痴迷橄榄球又爱吃甜甜圈的美国佬
football-obsessed, doughnut-loving American.
那是戈尔巴乔夫
That was Gorbachev.
不好意思 我总搞不清东方国家的这些领袖
I'm sorry I got Eastern-bloc leaders mixed up, OK.
我没有拒绝他 好吗 收回你的话
And I did not blow him, ok? Take it back!
好吧 好吧
Ok, ok.
天哪
God!
所以那是戈尔巴乔夫
So was it Gorbachev?
好吧 你知道的
All right, you know.
听着 我本来打算一会儿再跟你说
Listen to this... I was going to wait
可我这个人就是藏不住话
to tell you this till later, but I'm so bad with secrets.
怎么
What?
你脑子里长了肿瘤 快死了吗
You've got a tumor in your brain and you are going to die?
不 不是
No, no.
不是这些 好吗
Nothing like that, alright?
好吧 其实也有点像
Well, actually, it's kind of like that.
- 我祖母死了  - 不是吧 什么时候的事
- My grandmother died.  - What! When?
是的 我们吃饭前我爸爸发短信告诉我的
Yes, my dad texted to me right before we ate.
对不起 你怎么不早说
Oh I'm so sorry. Why didn't you tell me?!
像每个人都希望的那样
Everyone has been expecting it.
她活得够长了 而且一生幸福
she has lived a long time, had a great life.
她九十六岁了
She was 96.
你祖父死后没多久 她就去世了
She did not live much longer after your grandfather died.
不 有一年了
No... barely a year...
有趣的是 这女人还是个奇怪的圣人
The funny thing is that this woman was a freaking saint, ok?
战争时期 她做过护士 照顾我们所有人
She was a nurse in the war. She took care of all of us.
她从来没有说过别人一句坏话
You know... she never said any unkind word about anybody.
- 真希望我能遇到她  - 没关系的
- I wish I had met her.  - It's OK.
好吧 因为到后来
Okay, because by the end, you know,
她不想再认识任何人了
she just was not really into meeting new people.
一辈子都在笑面以对
I mean after a lifetime of being sweet as a pie,
自从祖父死后 她受到了很大的打击
once grandpa died, she got kind of awry.
是吗 那时她还在服丧吧
Really? It happens, she was in mourning, no?
没错 我父亲说她一直在等死
Yeah, well, my dad said she was just waiting to die.
他们结婚多久了
How long were they married?
七十四年了
74 years.
靠 怎么可能
Fuck! How is that even possible?
要是我们也一起生活七十四年 那得多老啊
How old will we be if we were together for 74 years?
那我们要从什么时候开始算起
Hm, when do we start counting from?
我想应该从我们第一次发生关系时算起吧
I guess from the first time we had sex.
好吧
Ok...
那应该是一九九四年
OK, so... 1994.
好吧 一九九四年 那还有五十六年
Ok... 1994... 56 years from now.
那时我们都九十八岁了
We will be 98.
天哪 你还能
Oh! Would you be able to
再忍受我整整五十六年吗
put up with me for another 56 more years?
我得搞清楚 我不知道自己
I need to know. I do not know
是不是还能忍你那么长时间
if I'm gonna be able to put up with you.
你想想他们见证的那些变化 真不可思议
It's crazy if you think about all the change they saw.
当他们见到彼此已经没有了最初的感觉
I mean, when they met, neither one of them had electricity.
他过去常常骑马带她上学
He used to take her to school on his horse.
毕业时他们两个分别是致辞的学生代表
When he graduated, he was valedictorian and she was salutatorian.
- 什么意思  - 祖父第一名 祖母第二名
- What is that?  - He was top of the class and she was second.
我敢说一定是祖母故意放水
I bet she knowingly got a couple of answers wrong,
你祖父才会轻松拿到第一
so that he did not feel threatened.
如果她想轻松一点 这就是最好的办法
Well, if she wanted to get laid, she'd better have.
没错 你知道 有人就是这么做的
Yes, obviously like you know who.
不管怎么说 在收到短信之后
Anyway, so I called my dad, right,
我告诉我爸爸
after I got the text, just, you know,
我很遗憾
to tell him I was sorry,
我想我可能说错了一些话
I think I got screwed up at some point said...
爸爸 你现在是孤儿了 我觉得这不好笑
Hey, dad, you're an orphan now, I don't think it was funny.
- 一点都不好笑  - 好吧 好像是不好笑
- Not funny at all  - Yeah, I guess not.
- 下一个是他 之后就是你  - 我知道
- He's next, then you.  - I know.
他告诉我说 我的祖父母
Well... he told me that my grandparents
想要死后葬在一起
wanted to have a joint service.
他们希望两人的骨灰能埋在一起
They wanted to have their ashes intermingled and be buried as one.
你祖父没有办葬礼吗
Your grandfather didn't have a funeral?
他们彼此立誓
They vowed to each other
绝不去参加对方的葬礼
they'd never have to attend one another's funeral.
好吧 我更希望你能参加我的葬礼
Oh yeah... I kind of like the idea of you attending mine.
- 什么  - 不是 我是说 我在想象
- What?  - No, I know... I'm imagining you in a suit,
你穿上正装 刮干净胡子的样子
clean-shaven for once,
挽着女儿们的手 我不知道 我就是喜欢
holding hands with the girls, I don't know, I like it.
- 你会活得比我长的  - 到时候就知道了
- You're gonna outlive me.  - We'll see.
我想我们俩只有一个人能看到那一天
I guess one of us will see.
你觉得我们也葬在一起怎么样
What do you think you're gonna go to the service with me?
- 去德克萨斯吗  - 反正不在巴黎
- To Texas?  - It's not gonna be in Paris.
你有多想把我葬在那儿
Ok, how bad you want me there?
其实我很愿意去 只不过机票太贵了
I mean I would come but it's really expensive with the flights.
其实一个人去会容易很多
Truth is it would be simpler to go alone.
你好
Oh, hello!
如果我不在那儿
Well, you know and if I'm not there,
你和你表姐就可以发生点什么了
it will be easier for you to fuck your cousins.
- 没错  - 你们那儿这种事很常见吧
- Yes, that's true.  - Isn't that common where you come from?
- 你还没回答我的问题  - 什么问题
- You didn't answer the question.  - What question?
好吧 你还能再忍受我五十六年吗
Well... will you be able to put up with me for 56 more years?
- 我也想知道  - 你又来了
- I'm looking forward to it.  - Shit, you're really working it.
你性爱时的甘露就如同陈年美酒
The nectar of your sex ages like a fine wine.
我长毛的西班牙小伙又变身希腊人了
O-o, my hairy Spanish lover is back Greek,
我现在是希腊人
I'm Greek now.
看看这个
Look at this!
这地方让我想起了
Wow, this place reminds me
我小时候看过的一部电影
a bit of a movie I saw when I was a teenager.
那是一部五十年代的黑白片
It was a black and white film from the 50s.
我记得 有一对夫妇走在庞贝古城的废墟旁
I remember a couple walking through the ruins of Pompeii,
看着那些在那里躺了好几个世纪的尸骸
viewing bodies that had been lying there for centuries.
我还记得那些尸骸
I remember the bodies, you know,
他们在睡梦中被捕的时候还紧拥着爱人
caught in their sleep still lovingly holding each other.
我也不知道为什么 有时候我经常在想
I don't know why, sometimes I have this image in my mind,
你搂着我 我们躺在一起
where, you know, we're asleep and you hold me.
在炽热的灰烬下被活活掩埋
What... of being buried alive under molten ash?
- 你就是在想这些吗  - 是的
- That's what you're thinking about?  - Yes!
这可一点都不好玩
That's not very fun!
我不知道 其实也没那么可怕
I don't know... It's not horrible I mean,
他们当中 有些夫妇中间还躺着孩子
they had some bodies with little kids sleeping between them.
那很好
That's nice.
是啊 我想我年轻的时候有些病态
Yeah, I guess I was young and a bit morbid,
觉得和自己心爱的人死在一起是很浪漫的事
I mean at that age you romanticize dying with the person you love.
那现在你愿意和我一起死吗
Now you want to die with me?
也许吧 你知道 如果是
Maybe you know if you were... you know,
我们在一起的第一个晚上 也许会
our first night together then,
可那是好久以前了 现在我才不
a long time ago, but now... no!
我想活着
I'd like to live!
我也只是想来点浪漫的 也被你破坏了
I just wanted you to say something romantic and you blew it!
算了吧 去你妈的 我搞砸了
Oh no! Putain de merde. I blew it!
等我们都九十八岁了 你可以再问一次
Ok, if we are both 98, you can ask me again.
不过现在
But any time sooner,
对不起了
Sorry.
这就是我说过的那个拜占庭时期
Hey... This is the chapel I was telling you about.
就有了的小教堂 已经有一千年历史了
It's from the Byzantine era, like a 1000 years old.
- 我们能进去吗  - 当然能了
- Can we go in?  - Yes, I think so.
来看看 有人吗
Check this out! Hello!
这是圣奥蒂莉亚的神龛 她是视力的守护神
It's a shrine to St. Odilia, the patron saint to eyesight.
人们从各处前来
People come from all over
给盲人留下各种小贡品
and they leave little dedications to the blind
帮助他们恢复视力
to help restore sight.
一定很灵吧
I'm sure, it works.
这里的这些画
And these paitings here,
让我联想到日本的和尚
they make me think of those Japanese monks, you know,
还有他们的无常思想
with their deal on impermanence?
天热时 他们喜欢用水在石头上画画
They like to paint with water on rock on hot days
所以画完的时候 就都蒸发了
so by the time they're done it's already evaporated.
眼睛被挖掉了 是和失明有关吗
Oh, the eyes are scratched out is that about blindness?
不 我本来也那么想
No, I thought that too,
但是那个看守人
but the caretaker guy
他告诉我 是土耳其人占领的时候干的
he told me that the Turks did that during the occupation.
好吧 我再也不吃土耳其食物了
That's it. I'm never eating Turkish food again.
好吧
Oh, ok.
那会让整个国际社会为之一颤的
That will send a shiver through international community.
好吧 那我再也不给土耳其人吹箫了
OK, fine. Then I will never suck another turkish cock.
那绝对会冲击整个世界
OK that's gonna have a global impact.
那太糟糕了
Oh that's terrible.
我忘了你是个秘密修行的基督徒
No! I forgot you're a closet-Christian.
在教堂里开黄色玩笑是不是太不敬了
Is it really bad to make blowjob jokes in a church?
有一点 但我们干过更过分的
It kind of is, ok? But we've done worse.
姑娘们又问起我们的婚礼是什么样的了
The girls asked me again what our wedding was like.
是吗 那你怎么说的
Yeah? And what did you say?
我就说 婚礼很低调
I said it was very low-key.
是很低调 以至于我都不记得这回事了
Very low-key, so low-key I don't even remember it.
贵格会：反对繁琐的形式，婚礼葬礼极简
很有贵格会风格吧
Very quaker?
我不知道她们为什么这么想要我们结婚
I do not know why they want us to be married so badly.
这对她们很重要
It is important to them.
- 这里是教堂 你想结婚吗  - 不想
- We are in a church, do you want to get married?  - No.
只是 她们那么喜欢那些童话
It's just all those fairy tales they like so much, you know.
记不记得 她们小一点的时候
Remember when they were little
她们看完每一部动画片
and at the end of every cartoon they watched
就会喊“他们要结婚了”
they'd be all like "They are getting married!"
甚至是匹诺曹和他爸爸
Even if it was Pinocchio and his Dad,
唐老鸭和侄子们 也不例外
Donald Duck and his nephews.
那如果我们要再一起生活五十六年
So if we are going to spend another 56 more years together...
- 怎么样  - 你希望我改变什么
- Yeah?  - What about me would you like to change?
- 怎么了  - 这又是一个答不对的问题
- What?  - That's another one of your "Can't win" questions.
- 我才不上当呢  - 说什么呢
- I am not answering that.  - What do you mean?!
难道我身上就没有一点是你想改变的吗
There is not one thing that you would like to change about me?
我这么完美吗
I'm perfect?
- 好吧 其实  - 就说一个
- Ok, actually,  - One thing.
如果你能改变一个地方
if I could change one thing about you,
我希望你不要再试图改变我了
it would be for you to stop trying to change me.
你真是个有手段的操纵者 你知道吗
You are a very skilled manipulator, you know that?
戳中你要害了吧
Well, I am on to you.
- 我知道你的套路  - 你这么想吗
- I know how you work.  - You think?
当然 我了解你的一切
Yeah, I know everything about you.
这里 我们从这里走
Here we go, let's go through here.
- 我觉得你没那么了解我  - 没有吗
- I don't think you do, actually.  - No?
至少你是我在这世上最了解的人
Well, I know you better than I know anybody else on the planet.
- 不过这可能说明不了什么  - 现在
- But, maybe that's not saying much.  - Right now,
- 什么  - 这样很好
- What?  - this is great, you know?
- 是啊  - 我觉得和你很亲近
- Right. Yeah.  - I feel close to you,
- 对  - 但有时候 怎么说呢
- Yeah.  - But sometimes I don't know,
你呼吸的是氦气 我呼吸的是氧气
I feel like you're breathing helium and I'm breathing oxygen.
为什么这么说
What makes you say that?
- 你看 我正想和你沟通  - 拜托
- See? I'm trying to truly connect  - Why, come on.
- 你却开玩笑  - 我只是想做自己
- and you make a joke!  - I'm just being myself.
- 不  - 我说的就是这个
- No!  - That's exactly what I'm talking about.
拜托 如果我们真的想要了解对方
C'mon. If we ever gonna truly know each other,
我觉得我们或许应该先看清自己
I think we probably have to get to know ourselves better first.
是啊
Yeah.
你还记得我那个朋友吗
Do you remember this friend of mine,
纽约的乔治
George from New York?
不记得
No.
不对 那是在之前 在之前 不不
Oh no, that was before. That was before. No, no.
总之他就是我一个朋友
Anyway, he was this friend of mine
他得知自己得了白血病
that when he found out that he had leukemia
知道自己活不长了
and he was probably gonna die,
他向我坦言 他的第一个反应
he confessed to me that the first thing that came to his mind
- 是解脱  - 解脱 什么解脱
- was relief.  - Relief? Of what?
在他知道自己只能再活九个月之前
Yeah, well, before he found out that he had nine months to live
他总是在担心钱不够花
he was always so worried about money.
而知道了以后 他的想法是
And now his thought was
太好了
"Great!"
这些钱让我花上九个月 绰绰有余了
"I have more than enough money to live the next 9 months,
- 我成功了  - 好吧
- I've made it!"  - OK.
接着他终于学会享受生活中的一切
And then he was finally able to enjoy everything about life
甚至享受堵车的感觉
even like being stuck in traffic.
他会很享受地看着人们 看着他们的脸
He would just enjoy looking at people and staring at their faces.
- 就是这种小事  - 那后来呢
- Just little things.  - And then what happened?
什么意思
What do you mean?
就是 他现在还活着吗
Well... like, is he still alive?
不 他死了 很久了
No, he died a long time ago.
昨晚我做了一个梦 我在看一本书
Last night, I had this dream, where I was reading a book, ok?
是一本失传了的经典 叫《流浪者》
It was a lost classic "The Rovers".
- 流浪者  - 是啊 到处晃荡 溜达
- "The Rovers"?  - Yeah like roving around, you know, wandering.
都是一些年轻人
It was all these young people.
- 真有这本书吗  - 没有 但它很棒
- OK. Is that a real book?  - No, but it was really great.
新颖 有趣 写实 充满能量
It was fresh, funny, experimental, had all this energy.
真佩服你 在梦里也能看书
I love that you read books in your dreams.
是啊 而且梦里的书都棒极了
I know, and they're always really good!
我会做一些大型动作英雄梦
I have, like,major action hero dreams.
我像个超级英雄一样 可以打破墙壁
Like I'm flying around like a super hero breaking through walls.
结果我就高潮了
And at the end I have an orgasm.
我会想办法让你的梦成真的 宝贝
I'm gonna try to make your dreams come true baby.
还在那儿
Still there.
还在
没了
Gone.
- 请给我信用卡  - 那房间付过钱了吧
- I need your credit card.  - Oh I think the room is paid for.
是的 但信用卡是用于
Yes it is, but the credit card is for
- 可能的费用  - 杂费
- possible outcomes?  - Incidentals.
原来如此
Of course.
- 华莱士先生  - 你好
- Mr. Wallace.  - Yes?
我是这两本书的忠实读者
I am such a fan of these two books.
我丈夫在我们第一次约会时给了我第一本
My husband gave me your book on our first date.
而你的第二本书出版后
And then when your second book came out
我们一起放声朗读
we read it out loud together.
- 您可以为我签一下吗  - 当然 没问题
- Would you plese sign it for me?  - Yeah, of course, of course.
我喜欢希腊版本的插图
I love the artwork on these Greek editions.
真漂亮
It's really nice.
你们怎么称呼
What are you names?
就写 致索菲亚和帕夫洛斯
Make it to Sophia and Pavlos.
好的
OK.
- 这是希腊语译名吗  - 是叫
- That's the Greek translation?  - Well it's called the ...
但我也不知道对不对
But I'm not sure that is correct.
- 因为你也没读过英文版的吧  - 是的
- It's because you never read it in English, right?  - Exactly.
太棒了
That's great.
您可以也签一下吗
Could you sign them too?
- 我吗  - 是的
- Me?  - Yes!
您才是灵感的来源 不是吗
You are the real mother, right?
玛德琳 其实不是 人们以为那是我
Madeleine, not really. People assume that it's me.
但其实完全不是 他想象力很丰富
But it's not me at all. He's got a big imagination.
求您了
Would you be so kind?
我丈夫会深感荣幸的
It would mean so much to my husband.
这书不是我写的 我不能签…我…
I can't sign a book I did not write... I...
- 她很乐意  - 好吧
- She'd be happy to.  - OK.
太好了 谢谢
Great. Thank you.
我很乐意
I'm happy to.
好的 谢谢您
Ok, thank you.
真棒 太感谢了
Great, thank you so much.
- 瞧瞧这个  - 真不错
- Check it out.  - Wow, this is nice.
有空调 我喜欢 我的天啊
Air conditioning! Oh, I love it! Oh my god.
还有浴缸
Oh wow! A bathtub!
- 我的天啊  - 来 看看这个
- My God!  - Hey, check this out!
斯特凡诺斯和阿里阿德涅给我们弄了瓶酒
Stefanos and Ariadni got us a bottle of wine
还有情侣按摩
and a couple's massage.
他们真好 我们得给他们留个礼物再走
They are so nice. We have to get them a present before we leave.
没错 也得记得给孩子们带点东西
I know. We should remember to get something for the kids, too.
是啊 当然了
Yeah, no, for sure.
- 我想姑娘们了  - 我不想
- I miss the girls.  - I don't.
这儿风景真好
It's such a nice view.
我只对一个风景感兴趣
The only view that I am interested in
什么
What?
就在这里
is right here.
怎么了
What?
有意思 我今天才发现
It's funny. I never noticed until today
你的红色胡子 都消失了
but all the red in your beard is gone.
那曾经是我对你着迷的一个原因
It used to be one of the things that made me fall for you.
够疯狂的
It's crazy.
不是消失了 只是变白了
It's not gone. It's just white.
你不会是想告诉我
You're not gonna tell me that
你的爱还得看颜色吧
your love is dependent on pigment, are you?
- 不是  - 不是
- No.  - No?
不是 但你知道吗
No, but you know,
姑娘们的睫毛上也有那种红色
I see the red in our girls' eyelashes.
我看着她们 就想起我们的相遇
I look at them and it makes me think of when we met.
你知道我现在期待什么吗
You know what I'm looking forward to?
- 什么  - 过后
- Yeah? What?  - After...
- 过后  - 对
- After...  - Yeah.
就是明天在你身边醒来
Is waking up next to you tomorrow.
你是说 没有妮娜和艾拉在边上蹦蹦跳跳
You mean, without Nina and Ella jumping on our heads?
没错
Exactly.
我好几年没听过你思考了
I haven't heard you think in years now.
思考
Think?
我以前一醒来 就能听见那声音
I used to wake up to that sound.
你的眼睛睁开又闭上
With your eyes opening and closing.
你的头脑 以两百万里的时速飞奔
And that brain of yours, going two million miles an hour.
我很想念 听见你在思考的感觉
I miss it. Hearing you think.
你刚才说你能听见我思考
When you said you could hear me think
我还真以为你能听见呢
I really thought you could.
原来是我睁眼闭眼的声音
But it was just my eyelids.
我真是够傻够天真
How dumb and romantic of me.
我喜欢的就是这个
That's my favorite thing.
我也怀念思考的感觉
I miss thinking too.
清晨再没时间思考了
No more thinking in the morning.
再没有晨光性爱
No more morning sex.
明天怎么样
Tomorrow?
我太期待了
I'm looking forward to it so much,
我觉得我要睡不着了
I don't think I'll be able to sleep.
我现在就想要
I'm looking forward to it right now.
好了
OK.
我们别说话了 开干吧
Let's stop talking so we can fuck,
然后睡觉
sleep,
醒来
wake up,
思考 再做爱
think and fuck again.
- 别接了  - 不行
- Don't answer it.  - No.
- 见鬼 谁打的  - 管他呢
- Oh shit, who is it?  - Who cares?
我说了紧急情况才打的
I said to call in case of emergency only.
希望不是姑娘们出事了
I hope the girls are ok.
是亨利
Oh, it's Henry.
亲爱的 你好吗
Hey sweetie, are you okay?
你到伦敦了吗
Are you in London?
这么快吗 好的
Already? OK.
不不 我们找到了
Oh no, no, we found it.
我们明天就寄过去 别担心
We'll mail it tomorrow, don't worry.
对
Yeah.
她们也很想你
Oh, they miss you too.
我会代你吻她们的
I'll kiss them for you.
好啊
Yeah.
好的 我会转告她们的
OK. I'll tell them.
和你妈妈相处愉快
Good luck with your mom, yeah.
我也爱你 再见
I love you too, bye.
好的
OK.
他很好
He's fine.
他说到了芝加哥就给你打电话
He says he will call you from Chicago when he lands.
为什么不让我和他说话
Why can't I talk to him?
你已经第二次这样了
That's twice you've done that.
你完全可以把手机给我的
Come on, you could have just handed me the phone.
你知道我很想和他聊聊
You know I wanted to talk to him.
他没时间多聊 他说他们在登机了
Well he didn't have time to talk. He said they were boarding.
他是什么忘带了 什么东西
What did he forget? What was that?
他的科学项目报告 我们明天就去寄
His science project, but we'll mail it tomorrow.
- 他没事的  - 你不该那样说他妈妈
- He'll be fine  - You shouldn't have said that about his mom.
什么 我说什么了
What? What did I say?
和你妈妈相处愉快
"Good luck with your mom."
- 拜托  - 我可没别的意思
- I mean, c'mon...  - I  didn't mean anything by it.
我知道 但这样不好
I know, but it's not good.
这样又让他想起了整件事情
You know, it just reminds him of the whole thing
我真希望你别那样
and I wish you wouldn't do that.
你以为我不说他就忘了吗
Oh, like you think he forgets?
真是典型的美式思维
That's so American
掩盖事实 当做从未发生
to just swipe it under the carpet and act as if it didn't happen.
我是说 为什么要让他想起来呢
Why put it into his head, you know?
或许他这会儿不想去想这件事呢
What if he does not want to think about it right now?
- 不会有影响的  - 会有一点 会的
- It means nothing.  - It means something. It does.
好吧 前些天我还和他开了个玩笑
Alright, I even made a joke the other day
说我和他妈妈应该
that his mom and I should try
来一场泥地大摔跤 才能一决胜负
to settle it in one big mud wrestling contest.
- 泥地大摔跤 你真那么说了  - 他笑了
- Mud wrestling? You said that?  - And he laughed.
或许他比你要有幽默感
He might have more of a sense of humour than you do.
拜托
Come on!
我们刚说过的
I dunno, we just talked about that,
你说他妈妈坏话的时候
you know, when you say bad things about his mom
他听见的是自己的坏话
what he hears is bad things about himself.
我可没说他妈妈坏话 我开个玩笑而已
Well I didn't say anything bad about his mom, ok? I made a joke.
开的不光是她的玩笑 也是我自己的
It's as much on me as much as it is on her.
我知道 我知道 只是 根本没必要提
I know, I know. It's just why conjure it up at all, you know?
我觉得他现在够大了
I think he's old enough now.
他知道他妈妈和我之间是怎么回事
I mean, he knows how bad it is between his mother and I.
- 是他妈妈和我  - 我什么也没做
- His mom and me.  - And I didn't do anything.
都是她冲着我来的
It's all coming from her towards me.
她恨我 没错 很久前我睡了她男人
OK, she hates me. Yes. I fucked her husband a long time ago.
或者是不是该说 他睡了我
Or should I say he fucked me?
是啊 没错
Yeah, right.
他妈妈和我本来就不和
Ok, making a joke about the fact
拿这开个玩笑 没什么大不了的
that his mother and I do not love each other is not the issue.
他不会因为这样就受到创伤
That's not going to traumatize him.
因为他已经受伤了 好吗
That already happened, alright?
现在你想转移你的负罪感给我吗
And now you are trying to transfer your guilt and blame me?
不是
No.
知道吗 反过来 如果你能一笑了之
You know, on the contrary, if you can make a joke about it
或许你就能好受点
maybe you'll be able to live with it better.
- 我是这么想的  - 好吧
- That's what I think.  - OK.
你说得对 一如既往
You're right, as always.
我们别说这个了 好吗
Let's just not talk about it, ok?
他妈妈要是个醉鬼
It's nobody's fault if his mom
或者虐待狂 可怨不得任何人
is drunk and abusive psychologically.
别那么说
Don't say that!
他得和她一起生活 想到这我就恶心
I mean it makes me sick that he has to be with her
但我想 法官会认为女人都有母性吧
but I guess judges assume that women have the mother instinct.
美狄亚：希腊神话中科尔喀斯国王之女，以巫术著称
她的母性就和美狄亚差不多
She has the mother instinct of Medea!
美狄亚吗
Medea, huh?
是啊 那不过是个希腊神话
Yeah, after all it is a Greek myth.
欧里庇得斯：希腊悲剧诗人
其实是欧里庇得斯的剧作
Actually, a play by Euripides.
一个女人 为惩罚前夫不惜杀死孩子
A woman killing her kids to punish her ex-husband,
她和这没什么两样
that's basically what she's doing.
她是在伤害他来报复你
She's hurting him to get to you.
不 她是利用他来破坏我的生活
No, she's making my life hell through him.
这才是她所做的
That's what she's doing.
但有时候 你说的话太过分了
But sometimes you say things that just go too far.
行了 别把你老婆的这个闹剧里
Ok, stop blaming me for everything that is wrong
所有的问题都怪在我身上 好吗
in this whole thing with your wife, ok?
- 是前妻 很久以前就是前妻了  - 好吧
- Ex-wife! Ex-wife for a long time!  - OK,
你当初就应该处理得好一点
you should have dealt better with it a little better back then,
她就不会这么恨我们了
she wouldn't have hated us so much, ok?
好 好 是我搞砸了
OK, ok, I screwed up.
你真是厉害 我们生活中
Alright. I just love this little rewrite you do that
有什么不如意 你都能说成是我的错
everything that isn't perfect in our life gets laid at my feet.
现在你要因为亨利 给我扣这种帽子吗
Now you're putting this shit on me about Henry?
什么帽子 你说什么呢
What shit? What are you talking about?
我来告诉你我在说什么吧
Let me tell you what I am talking about.
你这是要我搬去芝加哥 放弃我的生活
The moving to Chicago and giving up my life.
你说亨利需要你
Now that you mentioned that Henry needs you
你知道我什么感受吗
how do you think that makes me feel?
我很痛苦 知道吗
I'm miserable, alright?
我还怎么接受那份工作 你告诉我
How can I take that job now? Tell me, tell me.
- 我会有负罪感的  - 别这样
- I'll feel too guilty.  - No, no, no.
- 不行不行  - 那是你自己选择
- No, no, no, no.  - That's a choice you're making
要这样看待它的 明白吗
to look at it like that, alright?
女人就应该做养育者 这是天性
It is in the nature of women to be the nurturer.
什么
The what?
- 养育者  - 养育者
- The nurturer.  - The nurturer?
好吧 这个词我简直说不出口
OK, I can't even say that fucking word.
我就是本能地会对一切感到内疚
I just naturally feel bad about everything.
你还给我那种眼神 好像是我的错
And you give me that look like it's my fault.
什么眼神
What look?
就是怪我忘了把项目报告放进包里的眼神
That I forget to put in the bag the science project look.
- 我知道你怪我  - 我什么也没说
- I know you blame me.  - I didn't say anything.
对 你是什么也没说 你不用说出来
No, you did not say anything. You didn't have to.
- 错的从来都是我  - 好吧
- Yeah, it's always my fault.  - Yeah right.
我上班时在冰箱上看到
I read on the fridge at work,
那种用来拼句子的 贴在磁铁上的单词
you know those magnet words that people make sentences with.
有人拼了这么个句子
Someone had put together:
在牺牲的花园里 女人寻求着永生
"Women explore for eternity in the vast garden of sacrifice."
这一定是上帝的指示吧
Wow, that's a sure sign from God.
是的 这话真他妈是真理
Yeah, that line is so damn true
过去一万年来都是
and it’s been for 10,000 years.
但到此为止
But that's enough, ok?
我不想做这样的女人
I don't want to be one of these women.
就像结婚权对于同性恋
Like marriage is important to gays,
避孕对于维护女权的重要性
or contraception to women rights.
一旦我失去了信心
It's the same with giving up my hopes,
对于无数妇女
with the millions of women
我也不得不放弃她们的希望
that I have had to give up their hopes.
我不会这样的
I'm not gonna do it!
这不是我一个人的事情
This is bigger than me, this means more than me.
真精彩 连诺贝尔委员会都注意到了
Wow, bravo, the Nobel Committee is taking note, and just...
等下 我去通知一下瑞典方面 好吧
Hold on a second, I'm going to alert Sweden, okay?
面对如此多的女性压迫问题
I mean... it must be a full-time job
你一定是身负重任
carrying that much feminine oppression.
- 没错  - 遭受了这么多
- It is.  - You suffered so much,
在巴黎中产阶级家庭长大
growing up in middle class Paris,
后女性主义：上世纪九十年代女性追求性认同的主义
在后女性主义者时期
I mean the agony in the trenches
因索邦主义而苦恼
of the Sorbonne in the post-feminist era.
实在无法想像
I can not imagine.
你是个混蛋
You're an asshole.
知道吗 亲爱的
You know what, sweetie?
搬去芝加哥后
When I move into Chicago,
我一定要找到一套好房子
I want to make sure we're able to find a nice house,
缝制窗帘
and I can sew the drapes,
挑些搭配的床罩
And pick matching bed covers...
你今晚就打算这样度过吗
So this is how you now want to be spending this evening?
一直说这些吗
I mean, this is, this is what you wanna do tonight?
- 你先开始的  - 不
- Well, you started it.  - No.
是你一直念叨个不停
You're the one who will not shut up about it.
但如果真心想说 我是说谈论什么
But if you want to talk about it, I mean really talk about it.
那就心平气和 理性地说
I would prefer to have an unemotional, rational conversation.
你觉得我们能做到吗
I mean, do you think we could do that?
- 这可能吗  - 又开始了
- Would that be possible?  - Here we go.
要心平气和 要理性
Unemotional, rational.
你总是那个理智的人
You always play the part of the one and only rational one.
而我一直在不可理喻歇斯底里地闹
And I'm the irrational, hysterical, hormone-crazy one,
是因为我有感情
because I have emotions.
是 你以旁观者从全局角度谈论问题
Yeah, you sit back and you speak from your big perspective,
所以你说出来的一定是经过冷静思考的
which means everything you say is level-headed and true.
- 我也没有总是袖手旁观  - 整个世界
- I don't always do anything.  - The world is fucked
都被冷静而理智的男人的决策给毁掉了
by unemotional, irrational men deciding shit.
政客无故就计划开战
Alright? Politicians going to war for no reason,
商业巨头要榨干能源
corporate heads deciding to rape the environment.
钱尼·拉姆斯菲尔德 多么理智的男人
Chaney, Rumsfeld, very rational men.
钱尼·拉姆斯菲尔德 那倒是
Chaney, Rumsfeld, yeah, ok.
如果我知道解决办法
If I know a solution,
一定是经过深思熟虑才决定的
Very rational thinking behind it.
所以我们现在是怎样 挑战最终解决方案
Okay, so we are there now? Us versus the final solution.
行 这样 回答我一个问题好吧
Okay... let's do it, alright? Let me ask you this, alright?
你觉得亨利的生活
Do you think Henry's life
会不会因为你我关系更为稳定
would be helped by more consistent presence
而有所改善
by you and me?
- 又来了  - 不
- Here we go.  - No.
你不罢休 那就好好来谈谈 行不
You won't drop it. So let's talk about it. Alright?
我就问你一句
Let me just ask you one question.
汉克会不会因为你我关系更为稳定
Do you think Hank's life would be better served by
而在生活上得到更好的照顾
more consistent presence from you and me?
当然 他跟我们住一起会更好
Yes! I think it would be better if he lived with us.
- 对  - 而且他妈
- Okay.  - And I think his mom
是个酗酒又讨厌的贱人
is a fucking alcoholic, hateful cunt
利用我们在巴黎 我在生孩子的时间
that used the time we were in Paris and I was giving birth,
差点就把亨利合法驱逐出纽约
and almost dying to legally move Henry out of New York.
操丫的
Fuck her!
好 这我同意你
Okay, I agree with you.
虽然遗憾的是 我们不能让他离开美国
Okay, unfortunately we can not go and get him out of America,
但可以在想去见他的时候过去
but we could if we wanted to go to him.
虽然这是个大变动
Now I know it would be a big move,
但你还是考虑考虑如何
but what do you think? I mean
在美国就真的找不到让你开心的事情吗
is there any way that you could be happy in the US?
难道去美国就是不可能的事情吗
I mean is that just out of the realm of possibility?
也可以找一份差不多的工作的 是不是
I mean you could find a comparable job there?
- 差不多的  - 对啊
- Comparable job?  - Yeah!
- 你搞笑的吧  - 不
- Are you kidding?  - No.
为什么总让我来妥协
Why am I the one that always have to make the compromises?
天哪
Jesus Christ.
- 不应该是  - 别搞这么夸张 好吗
- I mean it should be...  - Don't be so dramatic, okay?
我 反正要搬去芝加哥这事
I... Well, moving to Chicago is
- 对我来说就是很夸张  - 我不是说
- Pretty fucking dramatic to me.  - I'm not saying
就该搬过去 我只是想谈谈这可能性
we should move. I just want to talk about it.
你就不能淡定那么两秒钟 好好谈谈吗
Can you be my friend for like two seconds so we can talk?
- 行 就一会儿  - 好的
- Okay, two seconds  - Alright.
记不记得你有一次
Do you remember that time that you were like
去接女儿们 迟到了大概三十五分钟
35 minutes late to pick up the girls from school,
你当时紧张死了
and you were so stressed out,
因为你知道她们在操场上
because you knew they were out there in the playground,
担心你是不是出什么事了
wondering what the hell happened to you?
而我 一直都有这种感觉
Okay, that is the way that I feel all the time.
我把自己的生活弄得一团糟
You know, like I fucked up, I mean,
之前一直没管他 现在我就想去接他
I left him behind and I just want to go get him.
你每次送他走就会这样
You always get like this when you drop him off.
你很失落 然后就开始跟我吵
You're sad, so you start a fight.
他没事的 他是个很棒的孩子 好吗
He's fine, he's a great kid, ok?
但事实就是他不再需要你像之前那样操心
But the truth is that he does not need you the way he used to.
你错过了可以陪伴
You missed the opportunity to be with him
在他童年每一天的机会
every day of his childhood,
已经错过了
You just did.
就算你再懊恼流泪 他也已经长大了
And you can cry about it, but he is growing up.
其他方面你是个很好的父亲
You're a great father in other ways,
离婚又不是什么稀奇事
you got divorced like millions of other people.
要说它适合吗 当然不是
Was it ideal? No.
但是
But...
听着
Listen,
如果一个月后你依旧想让我辞职
if in one month, you still want me to quit my job,
让我抛弃这些年积攒下的一切跟你走
and give up everything I've been working towards all these years,
直说就是了
just ask me.
但现在我这个想法是一直都有的
But right now I I feel the same way I always have.
我可以搬回美国
I would move back to the US
只要你的变态前妻能共享共同监护权
if that diseased ex-wife of yours give us joint custody.
但每隔一周的周末就会很难熬了 杰西
But every other weekend amounts to shit, Jesse.
一学期差不多就有三十天
That's less than 30 days a semester,
而我们为了那样的生活来放弃现在的日子
and I don't think it's worth it for us to change our entire lives
是不值得的
Over that kind of time.
- 你说的没错  - 是吧
- I know you're right.  - Right, right?
看 我倒成了理性的那个
See? I'm being the rational one.
但是 汉克处境太糟 他是无辜的
It's just... A shitty position. I mean Hank didn't do anything,
可他却被一直忽略
but he's the one getting kicked in the teeth.
人或多或少都会被父母的生活所拖累
We all get dragged through our parent's lives.
如果不是我 你的婚姻又会是另种情况
If it wasn't me, your marriage would have ended over something else.
- 这你很清楚  - 当然
- And you know that.  - Absolutely.
所以他可能会被贫困家庭养育
Or even worse he would have been raised
这更糟
by two miserable parents.
没错
Right...
我真是生活一团糟啊
I just really fucked that up.
你是说因为搬来巴黎和我在一起了吗
You mean you fucked up by moving to Paris to be with me?
- 不是  - 不
- No...  - No,
- 我就知道代价太大  - 我不是…
- I knew that was going to cost too much.  - That's not what I meant...
- 停 我不是这意思  - 我就知道
- Stop! That's not what I meant at all.  - I knew it.
- 我劝过你的 好吗  - 别说了
- I told you not to do this, okay?  - Stop it!
没错 当初我抛下一切搬去纽约
Okay... I moved to New York with you for two years,
跟你住了两年
and gave up everything.
但我需要回来生孩子
But I needed to be home to give birth to the twins,
因为双胞胎生产太复杂
because it was a complicated birth,
我还想妈妈能陪我 你也是这样想的
and I wanted to be with my mother and you wanted it, too.
- 对吧  - 是
- Okay?  - Yes.
- 这是我唯一要求的事情  - 是
- That's the one thing I asked from you.  - Okay.
唯一一件 你就要因此永远责备我吗
The one thing... and now you're gonna blame me forever?
别说了 好吗
Stop it, will you?
别说了
Stop it.
如果你不想搬回美国 我们就不搬
If you don't want to move back to the States, we won't.
就不用再说了
End of story.
好吗 我只是在想
Alright? I am just trying to find a way
究竟住在哪里 我的生活才能更稳定
where I can be a more consistent presence in his life
能让他生活得更好 就像一家人一样
and ideally I would like to do that as a family.
不然你想分居还是离婚
As a family or what?
这他妈是怎么说起来的
What the fuck does that mean?
我能感受到你说的每个字
I feel a passive-aggressive threat
都带有消极进攻的威胁
in everything you say,
如果不这样 你就会怨我一辈子的
Either do this or I will resent you for the rest of our lives.
是不是
No?
没错吧
Am I right?
我觉得…
You know what? I'm sensing something...
问题在于
I, I, I think the problem is,
你不想让我有一份稳定的工作
is that you do not want me to have a more substantial job.
从某种程度上来说
On some level you feel threatened
你因为我的成就而有威胁感
by my achieving anything
在咱俩的关系中会削减你的地位
that could diminish your status in our relationship.
我在这段关系中的地位吗
My status in our relationship?
我他妈在美国学校一学期教两门 好吗
I teach two courses a semester at the fucking American school, okay?
真是有地位啊
Wow, that's really some status!
不 你会在我有这样一个绝佳的
No, no. I don't think it's any coincidence
工作机遇之时
that you feel that way at the same time
却有那样的想法绝不是偶然
that I have a truly exciting job opportunity.
你很清楚 这一连串的都是你在瞎想
This whole train of thought is complete horseshit and you know it.
我问你
I have a question for you:
如果我们没有女儿 还有这些有的没的
If we didn't have the girls, all our crap.
我们还会在一起吗
Would we even still be together?
什么
What?
拜托 你他妈简直不可理喻
I mean, you're the fucking mayor of the crazy town.
你自己也知道啊 不是吗
Do you know that? You are.
我觉得 你必须搬去芝加哥
You know what I think? I think you have to move to Chicago.
亨利需要你
I think Henry needs you,
而我和女儿们就留在巴黎
and I think I need to stay in Paris with the girls,
接受这份工作
and take this job.
你为什么要这样 简直不可理喻
Why are you doing this? That's a ridiculous idea,
要我离开你和女儿们 不行
Like I'm gonna lose you and the girls? No!
你干嘛把所有的事情都复杂化
Why do you make everything so difficult?
杰西 你跟我在一起并不快乐
Jesse, you're unhappy with me.
你怪我让你离开你的儿子
You're blaming me for taking you away from your son.
你这样说也太莫名了
That is a completely irrational response
我只是在理清我的思路
to something I'm just trying to feel my way through.
听着 杰西
Listen, Jesse.
在这一个半月里
We just spent the last six weeks here,
我们过得很开心
and it's been great.
你每天都能思如泉涌
You've been able to write every day,
天气也十分美好
and the weather has been nice.
- 但我之前并不想来希腊  - 我知道
- But I didn't want to come to Greece.  - I know.
是吧 你无法预料下一秒会发生什么
Right? There could be a revolution any second.
人们会吃掉很多羊乳酪和橄榄油
People eat a lot of feta and olive oil.
表面上看起来很开心
And they act all happy,
但实际谈论的却是自己受了多少气
but they actually talk about how angry they are.
我就犹豫了
And it confuses me,
- 不知道以后到底会怎样  - 好吧
- And I don't know what's gonna happen.  - Okay.
我来告诉你将来会如何
Let me tell you what's gonna happen, alright?
就跟平常一样
the same thing that always happens...
什么事都没有
Nothing.
是 你知道吗 我没有一点自由时间
Right, you know what? I have had absolutely zero time for myself.
我还有一万封要回复的邮件
I have ten thousand emails I have to answer
- 没处理  - 等下
- That I didn't answer.  - Wait.
- 你以为我没有吗  - 随便了
- And you think I don't?  - Okay.
我整天都在做饭
I spend all day making dinner,
擦干你和你儿子在马桶坐垫上的尿
and wiping both you and your son's pee off the toilet seat,
你却在跟同行小说家侃侃而谈
while you talk to your fellow novelist:
哎呀哎呀 你真是个天才
Blah, blah, blah. You are a genius!
哎呀哎呀哎呀哎呀 不 你才是天才
Oh, blah blah blah blah. No! You are a genius!
我们跟亨利道别那一瞬间 你却说
And the second we said goodbye to Henry you suggest that
我还是得放弃梦寐以求的工作
maybe I should give up my dream job
就因为你情绪低落吗
because you feel bad?
那是 现在它就成了你梦寐以求的了
Okay, now it's your dream job.
今天下午你都不确定你要接受这份工作
This afternoon you weren't even sure you wanted it,
现在就成梦寐以求的了
but now it's your dream job.
你说话从来就不算数是吧
Do you ever listen to yourself?
没错 这就是我梦寐以求的
Yes, it is my dream job.
我虽犹豫但不意味着我不想接受
Just because I have doubts doesn't mean that I don't want it.
可是这跟你又有什么关系
Alright, but why do you care?
你每天都要在橄榄树下
Every day you go on your two hours
花两个小时在冥想中散步
contemplative walk under the olive trees.
苏格拉底 你真该穿件袍子
Socrates, oh you should get a robe.
是一个小时
It's an hour.
不 从你离开到回来
No, by the time you leave and by the time you actually with us again,
就是两个小时 换我就不行
Two hours. You know, I could never do that,
你实在太会享受了
you are very good at taking care of yourself.
我就自己照顾自己 还要操心别的事情
I take care of myself and everything else.
去哪里都是你收拾自己的 我收拾别的
We go somewhere you pack your bag and I pack everything else.
你从来都不会让我收拾女儿的东西
You would never let me pack the girls' shit!
从来都不会
Never!
因为你会忘了拿鞋子 尽带些脏内裤
'Cause there would be no shoes and plenty of dirty underwear.
是了是了 随便你说
Yeah ok, alright, so says you.
不 你有时间思考
No, I am happy that you have time
有关宇宙与生存的问题 我很开心
to contemplate the universe and have existential problems...
因为我没有 我几乎没有时间思考
Because I don't. I barely have time to think.
我上班 带孩子
I work, I babysit,
- 上班 带孩子  - 你消停会行吗
- I work, I babysit.  - Could you hold on a second?
我想上个厕所
I just have to tune up the string section.
知道吗
You know what?
在办公室我只有
The only time I get to think now
拉屎的时间能思考
is when I take a shit at the office.
伴着屎味整理思绪
I'm starting to associate the thoughts with the smell of shit.
这句话不错
That is a good line!
我要把这话用在书里
I'm going to use that in a book someday.
是啊 你一定会的
Yeah, I'm sure you will.
这句话就是整本书最好的句子了
And that will be the best line in the book.
还有 不准再把我或我说过做过的
And by the way, you may never ever use me or anything I say or do
写进你那些书里了
in one of your fucking books again.
女儿们的也不可以
and that goes for the girls, too.
行
Okay.
那是你不该跟作家搞在一起的 对吧
You shouldn't have hooked up with a writer, alright?
我不会把你写进书里的
You weren't in the last book or the one I'm writing now.
我他妈想写什么就写什么
See, I'm gonna write about whatever the fuck I want.
- 我们的生活还是你的素材  - 不不不
- As always, our life works for you.  - No, no, no.
别再那装受虐媳妇的丑样子
Don't give me this put-upon housewife bullshit.
好吧 现在已经不是五十年代了
Ok? This is not the 50s.
抱歉打断你受压迫血泪史的激情讲述
I'm sorry to ruin your perfect little narrative of oppression.
但事实上我才是
With the truth but I'm the one
那个每天在家操心琐碎的人
who's at home every day dealing with the bullshit,
- 因为你六点半才下班  - 是六点
- Cause you are working till 6:30  - Six o'clock.
你送女儿去学校 我去接
You take the girls to school and I pick them up,
这样很公平 是我们约定好的
that's fair, that's our deal.
- 天 我们可是住在法国巴黎  - 对
- We live in Paris, France, for Christ's sakes!  - Yeah.
- 你每天都要提醒我这事  - 我一生
- And you remind me of it every single day.  - I have orbited
都在围着你转 你知道的
my entire life around you and you know it.
所以我很抱歉这个暑假 你的确是度假
Ok? So I'm sorry if this summer's vacation, and it is a vacation,
因为我只看到你在海里玩耍
because all I've seen you do is frolic in the sea,
还有不停地吃希腊沙拉
and shove Greek salad down your throat.
但这些并不能说明你花了时间
Ok? But it's not indicative of you spending your life
做家务
In some kind of domestic servitude.
你知道我喜欢男人什么吗
You know what I love about men?
他们依旧相信有魔法
They still believe in magic.
小精灵们帮他们收拾臭袜子
Little fairies around who pick up the socks,
把碗洗干净
little fairies unload the dishwasher,
给孩子们涂防晒油
little fairies sunscreen the kids,
做好希腊沙拉后
little fairies who make the fucking
让你吃得像头猪一样
Greek salad that you eat like a pig.
行了 听我说 好吗
Okay, listen to me, alright?
你把我们照顾得很好
You are great at taking care of us.
这没错
You are.
我是说 你念着孩子
I mean... you take care of the kids,
想着朋友 心系整个社会
you take care of your friends, you take care of the world, alright?
在你成为一个母亲之前就已经这样了
And you were like that before you were a mom,
现在更是爱心泛滥
and now its only magnified, alright?
但是
But...
这也是我这些年一直强调的
and I've been telling you this for years,
你得对自己上点心了 好吗
now you gotta do a little bit better job
关心下自己
taking care of yourself, ok? You do.
然后不要再以关心我做借口了 好吗
Okay, stop patronizing me, alright?
我才是每天六点在家 不是六点半
I am the one at home every day at six, not 6:30.
我很值得信赖
I am reliable.
你请过保姆吗
Have you ever booked a baby sitter ever in your entire life?
没有
No.
女儿们的医生叫什么名字
what is the name of their pediatrician?
不要突击测试我
Stop quizzing me.
- 你不知道  - 好吗 你也太无聊了
- You don't know.  - Alright? it's really fucking boring.
是吧 行 知道吗 我每晚都在家
Yeah, okay... You know what? I'm at home every night,
做饭 给孩子们洗澡
and I make dinner, I give bath,
给她们读睡前故事
and I read bedtime stories.
有时候你在
Sometimes you there,
有时候你学校又有事
sometimes you at a university event,
或是巡回宣传
or a publicity tour, okay?
你灵感一来就一直在写作
When you get inspired you keep on writing,
有时候我也会有灵感的 你知道吗
I get inspired too sometimes, you know that?
你也想写东西 很好 你写嘛
You want to write? Good, write.
不 但你记得我曾是吉他唱手
No, but you remember I used to sing,
还写词作曲吧
and play guitar and write songs.
我还是很喜欢做这个
I'd still like to do it.
但我做不到 没时间
But I don't get to, there isn't time.
好 首先 写作并不是我的兴趣爱好
Ok... well, first off: My writing isn't a hobby.
好吗 其次 我希望你能挤出点时间
Alright? Secondly, I wish you would find the time...
不知道你怎么有时间
you somehow manage to find the time to
抱怨一天工作八小时
complain about eight hours a day!
我喜欢你唱歌的样子 好吗
I mean... I love the way you sing, okay?
我抛弃一切追随你
I fucked up my whole life,
就因为你唱歌的样子 好吗
'cause the way you sing, alright?
如果你在牢骚 抱怨 忧虑中
If you took one eighth of the energy
分出八分之一的精力
that you spend on bitching, whining, and worrying,
放在音乐创作上
if you put that energy into playing scales,
姜戈·恩哈特：法国著名吉他手，爵士乐史上的伟大琴师
你会成为姜戈·恩哈特这种人物的
I mean you would like be fucking Django Reinhardt.
好吧
Okay.
你忘了拿鞋子
You forgot your shoes.
你以为你赢了吗
You think you're winning?
很少有人能体会到
Very few people realize what it's like
对事业热情洋溢的女人有了孩子的感受
for an active or passionate woman to have a child.
有些朋友说 看吧
Some friends told me that you'll see,
迟早你会想着把她们扔出窗子
you'll wanna throw them out the window.
但事实上我一点也不想伤害她们
Okay? But the truth is that I never wanted to hurt them once,
但我想过很多次要为自己结束这种生活
but I thought about ending it all for myself a hundred times.
我很彷徨 而你又因亨利抚养权这破事
I was so confused and you were always away on a stupid book tour
总是参加售书巡回活动
because of Henry's custody shit,
而我也不想跟你徒增烦恼
and I didn't want to be a burden.
西尔维娅·普雷：美国女诗人，于创作高峰时自杀
现在我明白为何西尔维娅·普雷
Now I know why Sylvia Plath
把头放进烤面包器里
put her head in a toaster.
是烤箱
It was an oven.
不要给我咬文嚼字 你知道我的意思
Don't play with words! You know what I mean.
烤面包器 烤箱 都一个意思
Toaster, oven! Same thing.
你知道有多少次我独自面对女儿们的哭泣吗
You know how many times I was alone with the girls crying?
我完全不知道怎么办
With no clue what to do? Do you know
你知道当一个母亲不知所措时她的负罪感吗
the guilt a mother feels when she doesn't know what to do?
你以为只有你有这种感觉吗
Do you think you have sole ownership of that feeling?
你根本不明白好吗
I don't think you understand, ok?
你知道我内心对男人恐惧的是什么吗
You know what my secret fear is with every man?
是他们都想把我变成一个顺从的主妇
Is that they all want to turn me into a submissive housewife.
好吧 没人能那样做
Ok... no one could ever do that.
好吗 我保证
Alright? I promise it would be easier
要让你顺从什么
to fit your head into a toaster.
还不如把你的头按进烤箱里更容易
than to turn you into anything submissive.
我觉得我生育以后就没恢复过来
I don't think I recovered since giving birth.
她们出生时我完全不知道怎么办
When they were born I had no idea of
我…人们指望女人有天生的母性
what to do, I.... People expect women
好像是突然冒出来的 就像母狒狒
to have this instinct that kicks in. Like a female baboon.
但是我不知道该怎么做
But I had no idea how to do anything.
我很爱她们 但我做什么都是错的
I love them so much and I was doing everything wrong.
你还总不在家
And you were away so often,
打电话问我这一天过得怎么样
and calling me and asking me how my day went.
我都不知道怎么和你说
I couldn't even say it to you
我觉得不知所措很丢人
because I felt so ashamed to be so clueless.
- 我觉得你很棒  - 没有
- Look, I think you did great.  - No, I didn't.
不 你很棒 起码假装得很棒
No, you did, well you did a good job faking it then.
我
I just ..
我记得哄她们睡觉唯一的办法就是
I remember that the only way to get them to sleep
把笨重的双人婴儿车拖下楼
was to drag that stupid double
在午夜几小时几小时的散步
stroller down the stairs and walk them for hours and hours
走到皮加勒再返回来
in the middle of the night, all the way to Pigalle and back.
我有一次差点被抢劫
I almost got mugged once, I mean,
那家伙放过我的唯一原因
the only reason why the guy didn't attack me
是我看上去太惨了
was that I looked so pathetic.
过了三十五岁的唯一好处
The only upside of being over 35
就是不用担心被强奸
is that you don't get raped as much.
- 我看过这个说法 是真的  - 老天
- I read it, it's true.  - Oh Jesus.
我记得我有一次
Once I remember that I was watching
看到姐妹俩在跳蹦蹦床
the twins on the trampoline, you know,
她们好漂亮
and they looked so beautiful
我很开心因为她们开心
and I was happy because they were happy, you know.
其中一个用呼啦圈
And one of them had this...
跳绳用的那个
Hulla-hoop that she was using as a jump rope, you know.
另一个也想
But then the other wanted it,
然后她们就打起来了
so they started fighting over it, you know.
突然 被我看到了
And all of a sudden, I saw it all, you know.
所有这些遗憾 嫉妒 自私
All this, pity and jealousy and selfishness, you know.
我记得我当时就在想 好吧这就是普遍人性
And I remember thinking ... Ok, this is the natural human state
总是有点不满 永远不满足
Always a little dissatisfied, perpetually discontented, you know?
我是说
I mean...
看看我们
Look at us.
我们在这 在这伊甸园
Here we are, we are in... you know, The Garden of Eden.
但我们还在争吵
And we can not stop fighting.
我不认为人性只有一面
I do not think there is one natural human state.
而是多面的
The human state is multiple.
我是说 如果你看到孩子们玩耍
I mean, if that's what
想到的是这个
you see when you're watching the girls play
说明你很沮丧
that means you're depressed.
好吧
Ok...
- 可能是吧  - 我看到她们打架时
- Maybe I am.  - No. When I see them fight I see beautiful energy
看到的是生命中前行的无穷力量
of going forward in life and not
不让任何人踩在她们头上 夺走她们想要的
letting anyone step on them or take away what they want.
我喜欢她们打架 这让我看到了希望
You know, I like it when they fight. It gives me hope for them.
这是因为你把愤怒视作一种积极情绪
Well that's cause you see anger as a positive emotion, you know,
最后只会伤害你自己 你的工作 孩子和我
and you only end up hurting yourself, your work, the kids, me.
你从来不会生气吗
And you never get angry?
我生气时不会把它视作积极情绪
When I do, I don't see it as a positive.
你知道吗
You know something?
你写的那些书 人们来找我
The way you write in your books, people come up to me
亨利·米勒：美国“垮掉派”作家
以为我和那些鲁莽的亨利·米勒式的男人滚床单
and think that I make love to some wildcat Henry Miller type.
你滚床单的方式只有一种 每次都一样
You like to have sex the exact same way. Every time.
- 你说什么就是什么吧  - 亲亲 咪咪
- When you got it you got it  - Kissy, kissy, titty, titty
下面
Pussy...
我是一个兴趣简单的男人
I am a man of simple pleasures.
是的 非常简单
Yeah, very simple.
我最近打算告诉你个事
And I've been meaning to tell you that lately.
你不是亨利·米勒
You're no Henry Miller
在任何方面
on any level.
你知道吗 这房间让我浑身不自在
You know what? This room gives me the creeps.
我本来希望有一点古典的 真正的希腊风
I was expecting something quaint, like the real Greece.
这地方真的很…
This place is pretty real...
我们来这到底干嘛
What the hell are we doing here anyway?
全部都是安排好的
This is all too planned. Like,
我们本该度过一个不错的夜晚
we are supposed to have this great evening.
那种自然发生的
You know... there's no room for spontaneity.
离我们的生活远去了
It is all gone from our lives.
对吗 这太蠢了 根本没用
Right? And this is stupid and it's not working.
好吧 显然是
Ok... well, obviously, right.
我诅咒阿里阿德涅和斯特凡诺斯搞这些
And I curse Ariadni and I curse Stefanos for doing this.
好吧 夫妻按摩 这他妈的什么玩意儿
OK. a couples' massage?! What the fuck is that!?
把我都拉廉价了
That sounds sleazy to me, right?
我们没必要做啊
We don't have to do it!!! Ok?
拜托 这地方还不错 我喜欢酒店房间
C'mon, this place isn't so bad. I like hotel rooms.
- 很性感  - 我知道
- I think they are sexy  - Yeah. I know you do.
大作家之旅
Mr. Book tour.
雷迪森·希尔顿先生
Mr. Radisson Hilton.
我知道你在华盛顿开读书会
And I know that time
发生的事
when you were doing that reading in Washington.
那天晚上你手机凑巧坏了 多巧啊
When your cellphone supposedly broke that night. How convenient!
你以我们的孩子发誓
You swore on our kids
你没有上书店店员
that you didn't fuck that lady from the bookstore,
艾米丽
Emily.
对我发誓你没上什么艾米丽
Swear to me that you didn't fuck that Emily girl.
我不是嫉妒 我也不是那种人
And I'm not jealous because I'm not the jealous type
我只想知道真相 像个男人勇于承认好吗
But I just want to know is. OK? Be a man and admit the truth!
我给了你我的一生 我没别的可给了
I'm giving you my whole life, ok? I got nothing larger to give.
我没有给别人一生
I'm not giving it to anybody else.
如果你想否定我
If you're looking for permission to disqualify me,
我不会允许的
I'm not gonna give it to you.
我爱你
Ok? I love you.
我不想吵架
And I am not in conflict about it, Ok?
如果你想像列洗衣清单一样
But if what you want is like a laundry list of all the
听我列数你的过错 我奉陪
things about you that piss me off, I can give it to you.
我想听
Yeah. I want you to hear ...
好吧
Ok, well ...
从第一项开始
Let's start at number one,ok?
第一 你他妈就是个疯子
Number one... you're fucking nuts.
是的 你是 你去找找看
Alright? You are. Good luck
有没有其他人能忍受你
finding somebody else who'd put up with your shit
超过六个月
for more than like six months.
但是我 照单全收
But I accept the whole package.
疯狂的你 聪明的你
The crazy and the brilliant, right?
我知道你不会改变 也不想你改变
I know you're not gonna change and I don't want you to.
这就叫“接受你本来的样子”
It's called accepting you for being you.
好吧 我问你
Yeah, OK. I asked you a question,
如果我拖着婴儿车下楼
if while I was carrying that double stroller down the stairs,
在皮加勒被人强奸了
and getting ass-raped in Pigalle
你是不是在上什么艾米丽·勃朗特
Did you fuck that little Emily Bronte girl ?
我不知道什么艾米丽
Ok... I don't what Em...What Emily,
不知道你在说什么
what are you even talking about?
那个写邮件给你聊陀思妥耶夫斯基的人
The one that wrote the nice emails about Dostoyevsky.
杰西 你说得对
Oh Jesse, you're so right!
大司令官是俄语文学里
The grand commander is the deepest passage
根植的传统
of all of Russian literature.
如果你问我是否有履行对你 对女儿们
If you are asking me if I'm committed to you, the girls,
和我们共建的生活的承诺 答案是有
and the life we built together, the answer is a resounding yes.
所以你的确上了她 多谢
So you did fuck her, thank you very much.
你前男友母亲去世之后 你去看他
Do I ever ask you about the time you went to visit
我有问过你吗
your old boyfriend after his mother died?
没有 你知道为什么吗
No. You want to know why?
因为我知道你那法国屁股干的事
Because I know the way that your fucking French ass works.
我敢说你至少给那家伙吹箫了
And I guarantee that at least you blew that guy.
但是我也知道你爱我
But I also know that you love me.
我无所谓你复杂的人性
All right? And I'm OK with you being a complicated human being.
我不想过无趣的生活
I don't want to live a boring life
两个人只属于对方
where two people own each other,
囿于别人创建的
where two people are institutionalized
条条框框里
in a box that others created,
因为那都是胡说八道
because that is a bunch of stifling bullshit!
你知道怎么了吗
You know what's going on here?
很简单
It's simple.
我想我不再爱你了
I don't think I love you any more.
- 听着  - 我现在不想讲话
- Listen.  - I don't want to talk right now.
你一个人吗 还是在等某个人
Are you by yourself? Are you waiting for somebody?
是 我一个人 我乐意 我现在很生气
Yeah. I'm by myself and happy to be. I'm an angry person,
我伤害了我的孩子 工作 我爱的人
and I hurt my kids, my work and everyone I love.
那正是我的菜
Oh ... you're just my type.
我没心情 我来这就是想静静
Ok... I'm not in the mood. I came here to be alone.
我从那边咖啡店过来就在注意你了
Listen. I've been checking you out from across the cafe?
我不想惹你不适
And I don't want to make you uncomfortable
但是你是这附近
But you are by far the best-looking
- 最漂亮的女人  - 谢谢
- woman in this place.  - Thank you very much.
我想请你喝一杯
Yes, I'd love to buy a drink
随便聊聊 多了解你一点
or maybe talk to you, get to know you a little bit, you know.
你是来出差吗
Are you here on business?
你有男朋友
Ok, so you have a boyfriend.
现在没了
Not any more.
抱歉 你想谈谈吗
I'm sorry to hear that, God, you want to talk about it?
我不和陌生人讲话
I don't talk to strangers.
原来如此 我不是陌生人啊
Well that's the thing, I'm not a stranger.
我们以前见过 九四年夏天
We've met before... In the summer of 94?
你认错人了
You're mistaking me for someone else.
没有
No.
- 我们还坠入爱河了  - 是吗
- We even fell in love.  - Really?
我依稀记得有个人 甜蜜又浪漫
Hm, I vaguely remember someone sweet and romantic
让我觉得自己不再是孤身一人
that made me feel like I wasn't alone any more,
尊重我本来的样子
someone who had respect for who I was.
就是我
That's me.
- 我就是那个人  - 我想不是
- I'm that guy  - I don't think so.
我知道今晚一些你不知道的事
See? I know something about tonight that you do not know.
- 是吗 什么  - 很重要
- Really? What is that?  - Something important.
我知道是因为
You see, I know because
我已经度过今晚了
I've actually already lived through this night.
怎么做到的
How?
我是时光旅行者
I'm a time traveller.
好吧
Ok...
我房间有台时光机
I have time machine up in my room, and
我来拯救你 就像我说过的那样
I've come to save you just like I said I would.
- 拯救我什么  - 拯救你被胡言乱语
- Save me from what?  - Save you from
蒙蔽的双眼
being blinded by all the little bullshit, alright?
- 那不是胡言乱语  - 我确定那个你依稀记得的
- It's not bullshit.  - I assure you that guy
火车里偶遇的
you vaguely remember the sweet, romantic one
那个甜蜜浪漫的人
that you met on the train,
就是我
that is me.
- 是你吗  - 是
- That's you?  - Yeah.
我想我没认出来
I guess I didn't recognize you.
你看上去一团糟
You look like shit.
怎么说呢
Well what can I say?
时空穿梭太辛苦
I mean it's tough out there in time and space.
你正好相反 比我记忆里更漂亮了
You... on the other hand, are even more beautiful than I remember.
胡言乱语
Bullshit.
杰西 这不是游戏
Jesse, this is not a game.
你装可爱 哄我上床
You get all cute. You get in my panties.
接下来我知道我就要在芝加哥买花生酱了
And next thing I know I'm buying peanut butter in Chicago.
你这样搭讪是没用的
You're not gonna make it better by some little pick-up line.
不 我不是在搭讪你
No, I'm not trying to pick you up...
不 你误会我了
No no, you are misunderstanding me.
我是来是送信的
No, no... I'm only here as a messenger.
我来自未来
I just traveled all the way from the future,
我遇到八十二岁的你
I was just with your 82-year-old self
她让我把这封信读给你听
who gave me a letter to read to you.
- 所以我来了  - 我八十岁还活着
- So here I am.  - I'm still alive in my 80s?
是啊
Oh, yeah.
- 我的法国屁股呢  - 非常棒
- How's my French ass?  - Nice, really nice.
我无所谓我变成什么样了
I don't care about the way I look.
比现在的你更惹人爱
Let's just say there is more of you to love...
好吧
Ok, great.
- 你想我读给你听吗  - 我还有选择吗
- Do you want me to read it to you?  - Do I have a choice?
当然 如果你不感兴趣
Sure. I mean, if you're not interested in...
不不不 读吧
No, no, no. Read it.
好吧 听好了 亲爱的瑟琳
OK. Here it is: Dear Celine,
我从森林另一边给你写信
I am writing to you from the other side of the woods.
这封信会点燃
This letter is lighting a candle...
够了 我不会写这个的 太花哨
OK, stop it. I would never write this, too flowery,
“森林另一边” 什么森林
"Other side of the woods"? What fucking woods?
- 你在说什么  - 我可以继续吗
- What are you talking about?  - May I please continue?
好吧
Ok...
我把这个年轻人派去你身边
I'm sending you this young man,
是的 年轻人
yes, young.
他会是你的护卫
And he will be your escort.
天晓得他有多少毛病
God knows he has many problems
他终其一生都在
and he's struggled his whole life connecting
努力亲近陪伴他最爱的人
and being present, even with those he loves the most.
对此 他万分抱歉
And, for that, he is deeply sorry.
但是你是他唯一的希望
But you are his only hope.
瑟琳
Celine,
我对你的建议是
my advice to you is this:
你已经进入人生中最美好的年华
You're entering the best years of your life.
从我这个年纪回望过去
Looking back from where I sit now,
这段中年岁月仅比你十二岁和马修·瓦内萨
these middle years are only a little bit more difficult
彻夜欢跳比吉斯的“你的爱有多深”
than when you were 12 and Matthew and Vanessa
要艰难一些
danced all night to the Bee Gees' "How deep is your love".
我不知道是什么
I don't know what that...
算了 瑟琳 你会没事的
Anyway... Celine, you will be fine,
你的女儿们会成长为
your girls will grow up to become examples
- 女权运动的典范  - 不错
- and icons of feminism.  - Nice one.
是啊 我刚注意到
Yeah. Well you know I just noticed that
底下有一段附言
there's a postscript on the bottom.
也许我应该跳过 这些太无聊了
Maybe I just skip over, some of this is kind of boring...
好的 跳过 跳过
Yes. Skip away, please, skip away.
- 你确定  - 是
- Ok... you sure?  - Yeah!
- 好的  - 絮絮叨叨的
- Alright, well...  - Boring stuff.
好的 下面就是说什么
Ok... yeah, it's like blah blah blah,
经济注意事项啦 星座啦
financial tips, horoscopes...
好了这里 附言 顺便说下
Ok... Here it is: P.S. By the way...
顺便说下 我一生中最棒的性体验
By the way, the best sex of my life happened one night
是在伯罗奔尼撒南部的一夜
in the Southern Peloponnese.
别错过
Don't miss it!
我的性福达到一个新的里程碑
My whole sexual being went to a whole new ground-breaking level.
新的里程碑 很好
Ground-breaking, great.
是啊 你知道这什么意思吗
Yeah ... you know what that means?
杰西 能停止这个愚蠢的游戏吗
Ok. Jesse. Can you stop this stupid game?
我们不是你小说里的人物
We're not in one of your stories.
好吗
Ok?
你听到我返回房间说的话吗
Did you hear what I said to you back in the room?
你听到了吗
Did you hear me?
是
Yes.
听到了
I heard you.
你不爱我了吗
What, that you don't love me anymore?
我以为你不是那意思 但如果你就是那意思
I figured you didn't mean it but if you did then...
你知道吗
Oh, fuck it, you know something?
你就像个小女孩
You're just like the little girls
希望周围的人都生活在童话中
and everybody else you want to live inside some fairy tale, alright?
我来这是想挽回 好吗
I'm just trying to make things better here, alright?
我告诉你我无条件爱你
I tell you that I love you unconditionally,
我告诉你你很美
I tell you that you're beautiful,
我告诉你你的屁股八十岁都风采依旧
I tell you that your ass looks great when you're 80
- 我努力想逗你笑  - 好吧
- I'm trying to make you laugh.  - Ok
我忍受你一大堆臭脾气
I've put up with plenty of your shit
如果你以为我是条狗 总是回来找你
and if you think I'm just some dog who's gonna keep coming back,
那你错了 但如果你想要真爱 这就是爱
then you're wrong. But if you want true love then this is it.
这就是生活 不完美但很真实
This is real life. It's not perfect but it's real,
如果你看不到 那是你瞎了
and if you can not see it then you're blind.
好吗 我放弃
Alright? I give up.
时光机是什么样的
So what about this time machine?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
怎么工作的
How does it work?
很复杂
Well, it's complicated.
操作时要光着身子吗
Am I gonna have to get naked to operate it?
- 我是说  - 是的 真是这样
- I mean...  - Yeah, it's actually, it's been a real issue.
我是说不穿…衣服
I mean, I don't...clothes,
不能顺利通过时空统一体
they just don't travel well through whole space-time continuum.
哇哦 你真聪明
Wow, you're so smart.
- Jesus  - 时空
- Jesus.  - Space-time?
- 统一体  - 统一体
- Continuum.  - Continuum?
是啊
Yeah.
你知道我在想着你这封信
You know something I've been thinking about your letter...
你说你在伯罗奔尼撒南部住过
You know you... you lived in the Southern Peloponnese?
我们就在伯罗奔尼撒南部
Yeah, yeah and... we are in the Southern Peloponnese.
你说今晚会不会就是你八十岁时
And do you think it could be tonight
依旧念念不忘的夜晚
that you are still talking about in your 80s?
这个嘛
Well...
今晚肯定会是个美妙的夜晚
It was definitely one hell of a night we were about to have...